[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
COLTON OGDEN: All right.
科尔顿·奥格登：好的
Good afternoon, everybody.
大家下午好
Thank you so much for coming to today's talk.
非常感谢你来参加今天的演讲
My name is Colton Ogden.
我叫科尔顿·奥格登
I'm the course instructor for GD50, which
我是GD50的课程讲师 它
is CS50's new Introduction to Game Development course.
是中证50的S新推出的游戏开发入门课程
We started this last spring and we've been having lectures every week
我们是从去年春天开始的 我们每周都会讲课
so far for the last semester.
上个学期到目前为止
Last week we took a look at Portal, which
上周 我们看了一下门户网站 它
is a famous game by Valve, whereby you get a gun that can essentially
是Valve的一个著名游戏 在这个游戏中 你可以得到一把枪 它基本上可以
shoot these portals that defy the laws of space
拍摄这些无视空间法则的门户
onto different services in the game.
在游戏中使用不同的服务
Walk in and out of them and teleport through them and see through them.
走进走出它们 通过它们传送和看穿它们
And there are a host of interesting challenges associated
还有许多有趣的挑战与之相关
with implementing a game like this.
实现这样一款游戏
Now last week we looked at a simple version of it in Unity,
上周我们在《联合》杂志上看到了它的一个简单版本
but today we are joined by Dave Kircher and Tejeev Kohli of Valve Software who
但今天我们请到了Valve Software的Dave Kircher和Tejeev Kohli 他们
actually were on the Portal team and implemented
实际上我们是门户团队的一员 并实施了
all of the interesting sort of design and technical decisions
所有有趣的设计和技术决策
that went about making it work and making it fun and believable.
那就是让它发挥作用 让它变得有趣和可信
So without any further ado, this is the "Portal Problems."
因此 没有任何进一步的麻烦 这就是“门户问题”
Thank you.
谢谢
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
TEJEEV KOHLI: Hi.
Tejeev Kohli：嗨
So we're just going to run through.
所以我们只需要把它看完
Both me and Dave were actually students when we were hired by Valve,
当我们受雇于Valve时 我和Dave实际上都是学生
and we were hired to recreate the work we did as a student project for Valve
我们受雇来重现我们作为学生项目为Valve所做的工作
for Portal 1 and for Portal 2.
对于门户1和门户2
And today we just wanted to talk to you about some
今天我们只想和你谈谈一些
of the issues we had trying to create the mechanic for portals,
在我们试图创建门户的机械师时遇到的问题中
and then also some of the design, both the technical and some of the design
然后还有一些设计 既有技术上的 也有一些设计上的
issues that we had to tackle and work on to make the mechanic work properly.
我们必须解决和解决的问题 才能使机械师正常工作
So Dave is going to start off and then I'll jump in later.
所以戴夫要开始了 然后我会加入进来
DAVE KIRCHER: Hey, folks.
戴夫·科尔彻：大家好
As he mentioned, my name is Dave Kircher I was hired
如他所说 我叫戴夫·基尔彻我是被录用的
on specifically to work for Portal.
专门为门户网站工作
So I'm going to go ahead and preface.
因此 我将继续并开始前言
We're jumping through a lot of topics today and jumping very quickly,
我们今天跳过了很多话题 而且跳得很快
so this is a very video heavy presentation
所以这是一个视频很多的演示文稿
so that we can jump quickly in and out.
这样我们就可以快速地跳入和跳出
And I'm sorry if I go a little too fast.
如果我说得太快了 我很抱歉
I'm kind of optimizing for the stream.
我在为流媒体做一些优化
So hopefully, if I have gone too quickly over something,
所以希望 如果我说得太快了
you can review the stream and see it a second time.
您可以查看该流并再次查看它
So without further ado, let's start off-- just quickly.
因此 不要再费劲了 让我们开始吧--只是速度快点
I'm assuming that most of the people here
我想在座的大多数人
have played Portal or at least are familiar with it in some sense.
玩过门户游戏 或者至少在某种意义上熟悉它
That's just an assumption.
这只是一个假设
And that, for at least the technical portions,
而且 至少在技术上
that you are at least somewhat familiarized with 3D rendering.
您至少对3D渲染比较熟悉
If you're not, you may need to study up a little bit and then come back.
如果你不是 你可能需要稍微学习一下 然后再回来
But let's start off with just what is a portal?
但让我们从什么是门户开始吧？
A portal is a discontinuity in 3D space.
门户是3D空间中的不连续部分
It's a 2D discontinuity where we basically
这是一种2D不连续 我们基本上
define a 2D rectangle somewhere in space such that the front face-- sorry,
在空间中的某个地方定义一个2D矩形 这样正面--对不起
the back face of the 2D rectangle is defined as the front face of another 2D
2D矩形的背面被定义为另一个2D矩形的正面
rectangle.
矩形
So I've got my simple little example here of this blue portal
我这里有一个简单的蓝色门户的小例子
and this orange portal.
还有这个橙色的入口
We're defining them to be back to back, which gets us this result over here.
我们将他们定义为背靠背 这就得到了这个结果
So from the perspective of this little portal guy,
所以从这个门户网站的小家伙的角度来看
it should look like there's another room attached with a cube in it.
它应该看起来像是另一个房间 里面有一个立方体
But we're not actually moving 3D space at all
但我们实际上并没有移动3D空间
because otherwise we're trying to make sure that this perspective is
因为不然的话 我们试图确保这个观点是
true for both this guy and the cube.
对这家伙和魔方来说都是真的
And then you'd have this weird overlapping space
然后你就会有这个奇怪的重叠空间
that doesn't make any sense to anybody.
这对任何人来说都没有任何意义
So we do a lot of hacks to make it seem like space
所以我们做了很多破解 让它看起来像是太空
is folding in these interesting ways without actually moving space.
是以这种有趣的方式折叠 而不是真正移动空间
Another way to think of it is that it's a door.
另一种想法是 它是一扇门
If you look closely at this doorway, it's a very standard door.
如果你仔细看这扇门 它是一扇非常标准的门
It's a door like you walk through it, different stuff happens.
这是一扇门 就像你走进去一样 不同的事情发生了
But what I'm not telling you initially is that this actually isn't a door.
但我一开始没有告诉你的是 这实际上不是一扇门
For technical reasons, this level required a portal here
出于技术原因 此级别需要此处的门户
because we needed this room to move.
因为我们需要这个房间来搬家
So even though it looks like a doorway, it's completely fake.
因此 尽管它看起来像一个门口 但它完全是假的
And that it's a doorway that actually takes you
这是一扇门 它实际上带着你
about a half mile across the level.
横跨水平线大约半英里
But it looks like a door, and so my job on the Portal series
但它看起来像一扇门 所以我在门户系列中的工作
was to make sure that when we're creating portals that they
是为了确保当我们创建门户时 他们
feel to the player like a doorway.
对于球员来说 感觉就像是一个门口
And if you think of them in terms of a doorway,
如果你从门口的角度来考虑它们
all the interesting stuff for a portal happens on the inside of the doorway
传送门的所有有趣的东西都发生在门口的内侧
and nothing interesting happens on the outside.
外面也没有什么有趣的事情发生
And it's my job to make sure that all the interesting things that
我的工作就是确保所有有趣的事情
are happening outside the door don't happen.
发生在门外的事情不会发生
Because that's all stuff that doesn't make any sense.
因为这些都是没有任何意义的东西
So as you can see, I just flew across the level.
如你所见 我刚刚飞过了那一层
And that's the other side of that door that we just looked at.
这就是我们刚才看到的门的另一边
And I'm walking through it and it's a doorway.
我正穿过它 它是一扇门
So it's a door that doesn't take you a couple of inches.
所以这是一扇不需要你几英寸的门
It takes you about a half mile across the level.
它带你穿过平地大约半英里
Now we're into our rendering section, which
现在我们进入渲染部分 该部分
is basically one of my main expertises in the portal area.
基本上是我在门户领域的主要专长之一
So we're going be talking about quite a few things
所以我们将会谈论很多事情
and I'm going to jump in quickly, so hopefully I
我很快就会跳进去 所以希望我
don't spew it out too quickly.
不要吐得太快
That's kind of my problem.
这就是我的问题
So there are primarily two layers to render a portal of view.
因此 呈现视图门户主要有两个层
There might be more, but these are the two that I am primarily familiar with.
可能还有更多 但这是我主要熟悉的两个
The preliminary way that we did it with Narbacular Drop, which
我们使用Narbacular Drop的初步方法是
was the predecessor to Portal was with rendered texture.
是具有渲染纹理的门户的前身
And then when we got to working on the Portal franchise,
然后 当我们开始制作门户专营权时
we switched to a method where you draw it
我们切换到了一种方法 在那里你可以画出它
all in a single pass using what's known as a stencil buffer
使用所谓的模板缓冲区 所有操作只需一次即可完成
and I'll be talking more about that in a bit.
稍后我会更多地谈到这一点
But there are tradeoffs to each method.
但每种方法都有权衡之处
So with a texture, you have to have separate textures per portal view.
因此 对于纹理 每个门户视图都必须有单独的纹理
And if you have support for recursion, you
如果您支持递归 那么您可以
have to have many, many textures pre-allocated to do this.
必须预先分配许多纹理才能执行此操作
So your memory growth gets big very fast.
所以你的内存增长得非常快
You have to use the Painter's Algorithm or something like it
你必须使用画家的算法或类似的东西
to render your portals.
来渲染您的门户
You basically have to figure out the deepest portal you
你基本上要找出你最深的入口
can see into and render that one first.
可以先看到并渲染那个
And then any outward ones from that you're
然后 任何外在的东西 你都是
going to render them because they're going
去渲染它们 因为它们将
to contain a view of that first portal.
以包含第一个门户的视图
So you have to render it in that order.
所以你必须按照这个顺序来呈现它
And I don't know if it's true anymore.
我不知道这是不是真的了
It definitely was when I originally was working on the first portal.
这绝对是我最初在第一个门户网站上工作的时候
That you couldn't effectively use anti-aliasing,
你不能有效地使用抗锯齿
so you get small visual artifacts as you get close to a portal
因此 当您靠近门户时 您会看到小的视觉制品
because it would be rendered as a texture that doesn't quite
因为它会被渲染为一种纹理 而不是
render the same way as the rest of the back buffer.
渲染方式与后台缓冲区的其余部分相同
But it is the simplest to implement, especially
但它是实现起来最简单的 尤其是
if you don't support recursion at all.
如果您根本不支持递归
It is super simple to do because you can ignore the Painter's Algorithm
这非常简单 因为你可以忽略画家的算法
and just render all of them before you of your main view.
只需将它们全部呈现在您的主视图中
By contrast, when you render with stencils,
相比之下 当您使用模具进行渲染时
it renders the entire frame to the back buffer
它将整个帧呈现到后台缓冲区
so you don't have any extra texture memory requirements.
因此 您没有任何额外的纹理内存要求
You're doing it all in a single pass.
你一次就完成了所有的任务
You're starting from your main view and working your way in.
你正在从你的主要观点出发 并以你的方式进入
You actually have to nest it a little bit, so it's interesting.
你实际上必须把它嵌套一点 所以这很有趣
You are guaranteed to get homogeneous visual quality
您可以保证获得相同的视觉质量
because it's a single pass.
因为这是一次传球
The way you're rendering the rest of your frame.
渲染帧其余部分的方式
But it has a lot of extra complexity of when you render them
但是当你渲染它们时 它有很多额外的复杂性
and how you render them.
以及如何呈现它们
So this rendering portion is going to require
因此 该渲染部分将需要
quite a bit of spatial thinking.
有相当多的空间思维
So I'm going to show you this video.
所以我要给你们看这个视频
Basically this is a layout I'm going to use a couple of times.
基本上 这是我将多次使用的布局
Does this play?
这个可以玩吗？
Hopefully-- yes, OK.
希望--好的 好的
This is a room layout that I'm going to use a couple of times
这是一个房间布局 我将使用几次
where I've got an orange portal and a blue portal.
我有一个橙色的入口和一个蓝色的入口
And behind each one is a thin wall with some stuff behind it.
每一面墙的后面都有一堵薄墙 后面有一些东西
But hopefully to help illustrate what's in front of the blue portal,
但希望能帮助说明蓝色门户前的情况
you can see there's a whole bunch of blue stuff over there.
你可以看到那里有一大堆蓝色的东西
So yes, that is the example layout I want you to kind of keep in your head
是的 这就是我希望你们记住的示例布局
because spatial thinking is important to actually have reference.
因为空间思维很重要 实际上是有参考价值的
Let this finish one more time.
让这件事再结束一次
OK.
好的
Now this is something that pertains to both rendering with textures
这是与使用纹理进行渲染相关的内容
and stencils and I'm going to let this play once
和模板 我要让它播放一次
because I was advised that if I front load this too much,
因为有人建议我 如果我的前置负荷太大
it sounds confusing.
这听起来令人困惑
So while I'm playing this, I want you to look at the fact
所以当我播放这个的时候 我想让你们看看事实
that when the orange portal is on screen and when it's not,
当橙色入口出现在屏幕上 或者没有出现时
everything inside where the orange oval is
橙色椭圆形的里面的所有东西
looks exactly the same for when it is and when it is not there.
当它存在和不存在时 看起来完全相同
And so what I'm doing here is as I'm toggling between the views
所以我在这里所做的就是在两个视图之间切换
is I am teleporting to where the virtual camera is.
我正在传送到虚拟摄像机所在的位置
That's rendering out of the orange portal.
这是从橙色入口渲染出来的
Whoops-- come on, go back.
哎呀--来吧 倒回去
Oh, God.
哦 上帝
OK.
好的
I'm toggling back and forth.
我在来回切换
I'm looking into the orange portal, but I'm
我在看橙色的入口 但我
toggling to where the virtual camera is behind the blue portal.
切换到虚拟摄像机位于蓝色门户后面的位置
So if you remember back to when I said that we're
所以如果你还记得我说过我们
defining the back face of one rectangle to be
将一个矩形的背面定义为
the front face of another rectangle, that
另一个矩形的正面 即
means that they should be coplanar at all times.
意味着它们在任何时候都应该是共面的
And so if you think of my player model in terms
所以如果你从我的球员模型角度来看
of walking it to the orange portal.
把它送到橙色的入口
When I'm rendering my exit view, I should end up behind the blue portal
当我渲染我的出口视图时 我应该在蓝色门户后面结束
as I'm rendering out of it.
因为我正在用它来渲染
So it's important to remember that all the angles carry over from that.
所以重要的是要记住 所有的角度都是从那里继承下来的
And most importantly that whether you're rendering textures or rendering
最重要的是 无论是渲染纹理还是渲染
to stencil that nothing inside ever moves
模版里面的一切都不会移动
because it should be the exact same view angles,
因为它应该是完全相同的视角
the pixels should be in the exact same place.
像素应该位于完全相同的位置
If they're not in the same place, your math is wrong.
如果它们不在同一个地方 那么你的数学就错了
And this is especially important when rendering with textures
在使用纹理渲染时 这一点尤其重要
because one of the first mistakes I've seen several people do
因为我见过的几个人犯的第一个错误之一
is that they render the entire screen to a texture.
它们将整个屏幕渲染成一种纹理
And then they map the entire texture to this little quadratic here
然后他们将整个纹理映射到这里的这个小二次
and it looks all weird depending on how close or far away you are.
它看起来很奇怪 取决于你离得多近或多远
But as long as you project the--
但只要你投射出--
sorry.
抱歉的
Trying to work with videos is not the easiest.
尝试使用视频并不是最容易的
So as long as you project where the vertices of your mesh
所以只要你把网格的顶点投射到哪里
are in screen space, you can reuse those coordinates as your texture coordinates
在屏幕空间中 您可以重复使用这些坐标作为纹理坐标
and then it will line up perfectly.
然后它就会完美地排成一排
So that's the point of why it's rendering as one-to-one.
这就是为什么它以一对一的方式呈现的原因
You just want to make sure that you're rendering the same parts
您只需要确保渲染的部分相同
to the same part of the screen.
移动到屏幕的同一部分
Now I said I'd be using that previous layout a bunch
现在我说我会用以前的布局
and I swear I'm going to get back to there.
我发誓我会回到那里的
But this is a much better layout for rendering with stencils,
但对于使用模板进行渲染 这是一个更好的布局
and so now you need to learn a new layout just for a minute.
因此 现在你需要学习一个新的布局 只需一分钟
It's only used in stencils.
它只在模具中使用
But I've got these two portals looking at each other.
但我让这两个入口互相对视
They're kind of-- one stacked on top of the other,
它们有点--一个堆叠在另一个的上面
and they've got these light bridges that are just
他们有这些轻便的桥梁
serving to show you that transparencies are kind of a special case.
用来向你展示透明胶片是一种特殊情况
So I'm going to play it one more time.
所以我要再放一次
So you just got two portals facing each other.
所以你只有两个面对面的入口
And even though they're tiny, it does make an infinite recursion down
即使它们很小 它也会产生无限的递归
into the portals.
进入入口
So rendering with stencils.
所以用模板来渲染
I'm kind of assuming that for this part of the talk
我在某种程度上假设在演讲的这一部分
that you have some idea what a depth buffer is.
你对什么是深度缓冲有所了解
You may need to read up on that if you don't.
如果你不这样做 你可能需要好好读一读
The stencil buffer is very similar to the depth buffer
模具缓冲区与深度缓冲区非常相似
in that it defines rules and operations for when we can wholesale just not
因为它定义了规则和操作 当我们可以批发时
draw a pixel or when we do want to draw it.
画一个像素或者当我们想画它的时候
And then also while we are drawing pixels,
当我们画像素的时候
you can define several operations of how to modify the depth buffer.
你可以定义几个如何修改深度缓冲区的操作
But for all intents and purposes, it's invisible to the user
但实际上 它对用户是不可见的
except for the end result. So stencil buffer, a lot like a depth buffer,
除了最后的结果 模板缓冲区 很像深度缓冲区
but you're controlling the values in code instead of by vertex depth.
但是你是在代码中控制值而不是通过顶点深度
So before we render any scene using stencils, what we're going to do
所以在我们使用stenchmark渲染任何场景之前 我们要做的是
is we're going to clear our stencil buffer at the same time
我们要同时清空模板缓冲区
as we clear our depth buffer.
当我们清除深度缓冲区时
We're going to clear it to all zero values.
我们要把它清零
And the stencil buffer we were working with with Portal 1--
我们在传送门1中使用的模板缓冲区
I believe it only had two bits.
我相信它只有两个比特
I could be wrong.
我可能错了
It might be up to eight bits, but it's not a lot of bits.
它可能高达8位 但它不是很多位
So we need to be very conservative with the values we put in there.
因此 我们需要非常保守地对待我们在那里输入的值
So we're going to clear it to zero.
所以我们要把它清零
So everything in it is zero.
所以里面的一切都是零
And then we're going to render all of the OPEC objects in our scene
然后我们将渲染场景中的所有OPEC对象
and that's where we get to the visual I'm showing you here.
这就是我给你们看的画面
So you'll notice that none of the light bridges are here.
所以你会注意到这里没有一座光桥
None of the cool fancy window stuff is here.
这里没有那些很酷的花哨的橱窗
So all we've done is draw in all the opaque objects.
所以我们所做的就是画出所有不透明的物体
And then we take a special detour to render a portal.
然后我们绕了一个特殊的弯路来渲染一个入口
At this point, we've rendered this oval here.
在这一点上 我们已经在这里渲染了这个椭圆
And while we're rendering the oval, we tell the rendering system
当我们绘制椭圆形的时候 我们告诉渲染系统
to increment the stencil buffer wherever we render a pixel.
在渲染像素的任何地方递增模板缓冲区
So while we're rendering, all of the pixels here go from 0 to 1
所以当我们渲染的时候 所有的像素都从0到1
and that's an important bit.
这一点很重要
So we're going to be able to use that to tell the depth--
所以我们可以用它来判断深度
to tell draw operations where to draw from then on.
告诉绘制操作从那时起在哪里绘制
And then as soon as we've drawn the incrementing of the stencil buffer,
一旦我们画出模板缓冲区的增量
we tell all draw operations from then on to only draw
我们告诉所有的绘制操作从那时起只绘制
where the stencil value is 1.
其中 模具值为1
And we tell it to not modify anything.
我们告诉它不要修改任何东西
We're only drawing where there's a 1.
我们只画有1的地方
And then we can basically just forget all about stencil buffers
然后我们基本上就可以完全忘记模板缓冲区了
for a little bit and keep drawing.
再画一会儿 然后继续画
But at this point if you've been following along with the depth buffer,
但在这一点上 如果你一直在跟踪深度缓冲区
we've already drawn this nice little wall behind the portal.
我们已经在大门后面画了这面漂亮的小墙
So the depth is the same as this little quad here.
所以深度和这里的这个小四边形一样
And so the first thing we do is we render a full screen quad with depth
所以我们要做的第一件事就是渲染一个有深度的全屏幕四边形
at maximum value, which does really effectively
在最大值下 这真的很有效
make this a hole at this point.
在这一点上把这个弄成一个洞
And if we were to continue drawing opaque objects and things like that,
如果我们继续绘制不透明的物体和类似的东西
they would just show up in this hole.
他们就会出现在这个洞里
So then we start--
然后我们开始--
after we have drawn, after we have punched our hole in depth
在我们抽签之后 在我们把洞打得很深之后
and we've required that all draw operations have this matching
我们要求所有的绘制操作都有这样的匹配
stencil value of 1, then what we do is we just start over in our main scene
模板值为1 那么我们所做的就是从我们的主要场景重新开始
again and just draw it again.
再画一次 再画一次
But this time we move our virtual camera.
但这一次 我们移动了虚拟相机
Just the same operation as I showed you in the rendering.
就像我在渲染中展示的操作一样
It's one-to-one, we just have to do a matrix transform such
这是一对一的 我们只需要做一个矩阵变换
that we're behind the blue portal and we draw it again.
我们在蓝色入口的后面 我们又画了一次
And so, let's see here.
所以 让我们看看这个
I think I have a magnifying glass.
我想我有一个放大镜
So you may notice that we're in--
所以你可能注意到了 我们在--
whoops.
哎呀
OK, I can't apparently zoom and use a laser pointer.
好吧 我显然不能变焦和使用激光笔
So you may notice that the player model is there,
所以你可能会注意到玩家模型在那里
and then the exact same setup as I had shown you before.
然后是我之前展示给你们的完全相同的设置
It's the same set of quads and the oval again.
这是同样的一套四边形和椭圆形
And we do the exact same thing again.
我们再做一次完全一样的事情
We tell it to increment so all the values in this tiny little oval
我们告诉它递增 所以这个小椭圆形中的所有值
here are now 2.
以下是现在的2个
And then at that point we tell, OK, only render pixels with a stencil value of 2
然后在这一点上 我们告诉 好的 只呈现模板值为2的像素
and then we can just ignore stencil buffers again.
然后我们可以再次忽略模具缓冲区
We punch the hole again, and then we recurse again.
我们再打一次洞 然后再递归一次
And we go into a value of 3.
我们得到的值是3
At this point--
在这一点上
I'm going to get more into detail on it later,
稍后我将对其进行更详细的介绍
but we stop recursively rendering to stencil buffers
但是我们停止递归地呈现到模具缓冲区
because otherwise we'd draw a whole bunch of scenes
因为不然的话 我们会画一大堆场景
that we're not going to actually see.
我们不会真的看到
We pull a little trick that I'm going to get into.
我们耍了个小把戏 我就要上当了
So as we've drawn all of our opaques, we would theoretically do our detour.
所以 当我们画出所有的不透明区域时 理论上我们会绕道而行
We don't.
我们没有
And then we finish by drawing all of our translucent objects.
然后我们画出我们所有的半透明物体作为结束
And I know it's very tiny to see them there,
我知道在那里看到它们是很小的
but it will become more apparent later.
但这一点稍后会变得更加明显
I think that-- sorry, that's actually our rendering trick.
我认为--抱歉 这实际上是我们的渲染技巧
And there, now we've actually drawn the translucence in that view.
在那里 现在我们实际上已经在该视图中绘制了半透明
And I know this is very small, but it'll make more sense at recursion level 1.
我知道这很小 但在递归级别1会更有意义
So as we draw our translucent objects, we're
因此 当我们绘制半透明对象时 我们
still all confined to drawing where stencil value is 2.
仍然仅限于模板值为2的绘图
And then once we are done drawing all of our translucent objects,
然后一旦我们画完了所有的半透明物体
we render the portal oval--
我们将门户呈现为椭圆形--
whoops, sorry, sorry.
哎呀 对不起 对不起
I'm going to pretend that we're drawing to the big oval
我要假装我们要画到大椭圆形
here because it's easier to see.
在这里 因为它更容易看到
We would draw another quad at this level, sort of like a window,
我们会在这个高度画另一个四边形 有点像窗户
telling it to decrement the stencil value back to 1.
告诉它将模板值递减回1
I'm sorry, I need to take a step back.
对不起 我需要退后一步
We need to replace depth so that there's no longer a hole there.
我们需要更换深度 这样那里就不再有洞了
So we draw the full screen quad with depth equal to the portal plane
因此 我们绘制全屏四边形 深度等于入口平面
while still restricting to the nested view and then we decrement.
同时仍然限于嵌套视图 然后我们递减
Sorry.
抱歉的
So by the time we've done decrementing, that
所以 当我们完成减量的时候
means all of these pixels inside this first recursion are now 1 again.
意味着第一次递归中的所有像素现在再次为1
Every single one of them is a 1 on the stencil value.
它们中的每一个都是模具值上的1
So we can continue rendering the translucence from the first recursion
因此 我们可以从第一次递归开始继续渲染半透明
just like we did when we're doing the opaques.
就像我们做不透明的时候一样
We can say just restrict your drawing to all stencil value 1.
我们可以说 只要把你的画限制在所有模板值1
And then we finish our translucence there.
然后我们在那里完成我们的半透明
We do the exact same thing again while we're going back to the main view.
当我们回到主视图时 我们再次做同样的事情
We fix up our depth and then we decrement the stencil values again.
我们固定我们的深度 然后我们再次减小模板的值
And then we just finish out our main scene,
然后我们就完成了我们的主要场景
and now you have portals drawn using stencils.
现在 您已经使用模板绘制了门户
They required no extra texture memory whatsoever.
它们不需要任何额外的纹理内存
So bouncing back to the scene that we had
所以回到我们曾经有过的场景
shown before this, one of the things that we had to solve pretty quickly
在此之前 我们必须迅速解决的一件事
is when you have some object in the middle of a portal,
就是当你在门户中间有一些物体时
you have to be able to see it in two places at once.
你必须能够同时在两个地方看到它
And the way that we do this is we literally just look up
我们做到这一点的方法是 我们只需抬头看
every piece and rendering geometry.
每一块和渲染几何体
It uses every texture and replicate it and teleport it every single frame
它使用每一种纹理 复制并传送每一帧
to wherever the original is.
无论原作在哪里
And while we're replicating, this object over here.
当我们复制的时候 这个物体在这里
You can see that it's slightly more in front of the orange portal.
你可以看到它在橙色入口的前面稍微多一点
So basically the rules are defined such that whichever object--
因此 规则基本上是这样定义的 即无论哪个对象--
whichever side of the object has its origin in front of the portal
对象的哪一侧的原点在门户前面
is the master.
才是主宰
And the origin for this cube is right in its middle,
这个立方体的原点就在它的中间
and origin is just a term that we use to define the one point in space that
而原点只是我们用来定义空间中一点的一个术语
defines where this object is.
定义此对象的位置
So usually it's in the center of an object.
所以通常它在一个物体的中心
Not always, but that means this is the real one.
并不总是这样 但这意味着这是真的
And this is our complete and utter fake one
这是我们的全套和彻头彻尾的假的
that we have to do for every single object that is penetrating the portal.
我们必须为每一个穿透入口的物体做这件事
Now when we duplicate geometry and whether we
现在 当我们复制几何体时 我们是否
not-- whether we duplicate or not, we have another problem to solve.
不--无论我们是否复制 我们都有另一个问题要解决
I'm going to let this video play.
我要让这段视频播放
I'm going to be toggling a broken part on and off.
我要时断时续地切换一个破碎的部分
So when the cube is not behind the wall, that's the fixed version.
因此 当立方体不在墙后时 这是固定的版本
And when you can see it behind the wall, that's the broken version.
当你可以在墙后看到它时 那就是破碎的版本
So if you think about replicating geometry,
因此 如果你考虑复制几何图形
we have replicated the entire model to this orange portal.
我们已经将整个模型复制到这个橙色门户
Which means all the stuff that is supposed
这意味着所有应该做的事情
to be in front of the blue portal is also sticking behind this wall.
站在蓝色门户前面 也就是坚守在这堵墙后面
Because once again, we have defined the two faces to be coplanar.
因为我们又一次定义了这两个面是共面的
So what we have to do is we have to use what's known as a clip plane
所以我们要做的就是使用所谓的剪切面
to tell the rendering system, you know what?
告诉渲染系统 你知道吗？
Just don't draw any pixels if the mesh is on this half of this half space.
如果网格在这半个空间的这一半上 不要画任何像素
And we define the half space to be the portal plane.
我们将半空间定义为入口平面
And we can turn this clip plane on and off
我们可以打开和关闭这个剪裁平面
as we're drawing objects inside the portal plane
当我们在入口平面内绘制对象时
and that's what makes it work.
这就是它发挥作用的原因
Otherwise it would clip the whole world.
否则 它将扼杀整个世界
I'm going to play the video again.
我要再放一次录像带
It happens.
常有的事
So, yeah, we're just telling it, hey, you
所以 是的 我们只是在说 嘿 你
need to just ignore every single pixel that's on that half of all of space.
只需忽略所有空间的一半上的每一个像素
Don't draw them.
不要画它们
And that makes it so it doesn't seem like it's
这让它看起来不像是
sticking out the back in weird ways that people don't understand.
以一种人们不理解的奇怪方式从后面露出来
OK, now this is a very similar concept.
好的 现在这是一个非常相似的概念
Something that we coined the term "banana juice" for.
一种我们创造了术语“香蕉汁”的东西
Even back in Narbacular Drop because it's just confusing.
甚至回到纳巴卡拉 因为这太让人困惑了
And I know you're asking yourself, what in the heck is "banana juice?"
我知道你在问自己 “香蕉汁”到底是什么？
That doesn't make any sense.
这没有任何意义
So we decided to use a completely insane term for it.
所以我们决定用一个完全疯狂的词来形容它
Because even our technical shorthand for describing the problem
因为即使是我们描述问题的技术速记
didn't accurately describe what it was.
没有准确地描述它是什么
So we decided to use a term that--
所以我们决定用一个术语--
it was obvious that explanation was needed.
很明显 需要做出解释
So what we've got here is I've got my orange camera
所以我们现在看到的是我拿着我的橙色相机
and I'm looking into the orange portal here.
我正看着这里的橙色入口
And that means I've got my blue camera, virtual camera here,
这意味着我有我的蓝色摄像头 虚拟摄像头
looking out of the blue portal.
从蓝色的传送门往外看
And if you remember back to my example, we've
如果你还记得我的例子 我们已经
got this geometry that's behind the blue portal.
这是蓝色入口后面的几何图形
And it's between the blue virtual camera and the portal,
它在蓝色虚拟摄像机和入口之间
and if we render that, it's going to look completely broken.
如果我们渲染它 它会看起来完全坏了
So "banana juice" is a term to define this broken stuff
所以“香蕉汁”是一个术语 用来定义这种碎东西
that you would see if you were looking behind the thin wall.
如果你往薄墙后面看 你就会看到
And I have a video of it here.
我这里有一段视频
I believe I'm toggling back and forth between views just like when
我相信我在视图之间来回切换 就像当
I showed you rendering as one-to-one.
我向你展示了一对一的渲染
And that's me turning off the clip plane.
这是我关掉剪切机的照片
This is what it would look like if we were in the virtual space and the clip
这就是如果我们在虚拟空间和剪辑中的样子
planes were not enabled and then I go back to our main view.
飞机没有启用 然后我回到我们的主视图
And you'll see as I move around in a second that it looks completely broken
你会看到 当我在一秒钟内走动时 它看起来完全坏了
and it kind of breaks your brain if you don't understand what's going on.
如果你不明白发生了什么 这会让你的大脑崩溃
So that is "banana juice," and you fix it exactly the same way
所以这就是“香蕉汁” 你用完全相同的方法来修复它
as with the entity clipping.
与实体剪裁一样
You have clip models, but what we do is I'm going to replay the video here.
你有剪辑模型 但我们要做的是 我要在这里重播视频
If you're watching, this entire part of the level is now clipped.
如果你正在观看 这一关卡的整个部分现在都被剪裁了
So what we do is while we're rendering a virtual camera,
所以我们要做的是 当我们渲染一个虚拟摄像机时
we just clip the entire world behind the portal plane.
我们只需在传送门平面后面剪掉整个世界
All of it.
所有的一切
Everything that's back there.
后面的一切
So that's how you fix "banana juice" too.
所以这也是你修复“香蕉汁”的方法
It's not super difficult once you understand it,
一旦你理解了 就不是很难了
but I can tell you it took me about two days
但我可以告诉你 我花了大约两天时间
to figure out exactly what was going on when I originally saw it.
弄清楚我第一次看到它的时候到底发生了什么
It just didn't make any sense.
这完全说不通
So moving on again, I know we're jumping a lot and I'm sorry.
所以再来看一遍 我知道我们跳了很多 我很抱歉
We're just going to keep moving on at a quick pace.
我们只会继续以快节奏前进
So infinite recursion is something that people kind of expected
所以无限递归是人们所期待的东西
to see when they were playing portal.
看看他们什么时候在玩传送门
If you ever played the original Narbacular Drop,
如果你曾经演奏过最初的纳巴卡勒空降
we didn't support any form of recursion and it was kind of a letdown.
我们不支持任何形式的递归 这有点令人失望
So I'm going to go into how this works.
因此 我将深入探讨这是如何工作的
So in this view, you can see that we have this blue portal.
在这个视图中 您可以看到我们有一个蓝色的门户
That's our first recursion right here and it's taking up most of the screen.
这是我们在这里的第一次递归 它占据了屏幕的大部分
And then we've got this blue portal that you can see the entirety of it.
然后我们有一个蓝色的入口 你可以看到它的整体
That's our second recursion.
这是我们的第二次递归
And this one in here is completely and totally fake.
而这里的这张完全是假的
So that one, there is no portal there whatsoever.
所以那一个 那里无论如何都没有入口
What we're doing is we're taking whatever we see
我们所做的就是把我们看到的一切
of this portal, the second recursion.
这个门户的第二次递归
We're taking that exact view from the previous frame.
我们采用的是上一帧中的完全相同的观点
We're taking those pixels and then we're basically doing a fix up
我们获取这些像素 然后我们基本上是在做一个修复
in case you moved your camera around.
以防你移动你的相机
And we're applying the texture coordinates from the second portal
我们正在应用来自第二个门户的纹理坐标
to where the third portal would be.
第三个传送门应该在哪里
And by a completely fake, I mean we didn't even render this blue oval.
说到完全假的 我的意思是我们甚至没有绘制这个蓝色的椭圆形
That's just a copy of this oval right here.
这只是这个椭圆形的复制品
So it's the exact same thing as if you point a video camera at a video monitor
所以这就像你把摄像机对准视频监视器一样
that's showing what it's recording.
这是在显示它正在录制的内容
You get that feedback loop.
你得到了反馈循环
But we have access to a little bit of extra special math.
但我们可以接触到一些额外的特殊数学知识
That means that we don't get that weird snaking
这意味着我们不会有那种奇怪的蛇
effect if you move it back and forth.
如果你来回移动它 就会产生效果
We can fix it up quickly.
我们可以很快把它修好
But this video is actually going to show you about how this quickly breaks down.
但这段视频实际上将向你展示这一点是如何迅速分解的
Because if you're thinking ahead, you might
因为如果你有先见之明 你可能
be wondering what happens if you can't see all the second portal.
想知道如果你看不到所有的第二个入口会发生什么
And the answer is that we stretch it.
答案是我们把它拉长
So as you watch the third one, it just kind of stretches off in weird ways.
所以当你看第三部的时候 它会以一种奇怪的方式伸展开来
Which is a problem that, if we spend a bunch of time,
这是一个问题 如果我们花很多时间
we probably could have fixed.
我们本可以修好的
But in game development, sometimes you just call it good enough
但在游戏开发中 有时你只是说它足够好
and move on because I bet anybody that played the original Portal never
然后继续前进 因为我打赌任何玩过原版门户的人都不会
noticed this whatsoever.
注意到了这一点
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
So another breakdown of it, which I find personally annoying and interesting
所以它的另一个细分 我个人觉得既恼人又有趣
at the same time.
在同一时间
I'm just going to show the video of it first.
我只想先把它的视频放出来
As I'm walking, you'll notice at the third recursion, which is completely
当我走的时候 你会注意到第三次递归 这是完全
fake, you're going to see a pop.
假的 你会看到一个流行音乐
You're going to see every single time I walk through a portal, it pops around.
你会看到 每次我走过一个传送门 它都会跳出来
So this is actually fairly easy to explain once you understand--
所以这实际上很容易解释 一旦你理解了--
really understand how the hack works.
真正了解黑客是如何工作的
So if you look at my visualization here, this
所以 如果你看我的视觉化 这是
is what the actual recursion would look like if we actually did it.
是实际递归的样子 如果我们真的这样做了
So we've got a couple of portals here at these blue lines.
所以我们在这些蓝线上有几个入口
And so inside our first portal that we're fairly close to,
所以在我们的第一个入口里面 我们离它很近
our field of view is really wide.
我们的视野真的很广
And then as we get to our second portal, it gets really narrow really fast.
然后 当我们到达我们的第二个入口时 它变得非常窄 非常快
But then as we get to the third, it narrows even more.
但当我们到达第三个地方时 它就变得更窄了
And then the fourth, it narrows even more.
然后第四个 它变得更窄了
But since we're cutting and pasting, the second recursion,
但是因为我们是剪切和粘贴 所以第二次递归
if you look down here on this visualization, this is the hack.
如果你往下看这张图 这就是黑客
So we take this one, the second visualization, and copy
所以我们拿这个 第二个可视化的 然后复制
and paste it onto the third and onto the fourth.
然后把它粘贴到第三个和第四个上
And you can notice that this doesn't converge at all.
你可以注意到 这根本不收敛
It doesn't narrow.
它不会缩小范围
So we're seeing the same amount of wall around each
所以我们看到了同样数量的围墙
of the recursions no matter what, no matter how narrow this magenta cone is.
不管什么情况 不管这个洋红锥体有多窄
So as we walk through a portal, the magenta cone,
所以当我们穿过传送门时 洋红锥体
we're picking a portal that's further off because now
我们选择了一个更远的入口 因为现在
that's the second recursion after we walk through a portal.
这是我们穿过门户之后的第二次递归
So it starts off narrow, which is closer to what
所以它开始的范围很窄 更接近于
it should look like at infinity.
它应该看起来是无穷大的
It should narrow to basically where you're seeing a blue tube.
它应该会缩小到你所看到的蓝色管子的位置
But then as we walk closer and closer to the main portal,
但是当我们走得越来越近的时候
then it's going to widen and widen and widen.
然后它会变宽 变宽 变宽
And so there's just a pop where it snaps into place.
所以只有一声砰的一声 它就会突然就位
So hopefully that made sense.
因此 希望这是有意义的
And once again, completely changing topics because we
再一次 完全改变话题 因为我们
got so many things to cover.
有那么多东西要讲
So when we're rendering portals, we have to have
因此 当我们呈现门户时 我们必须
a mix of rendering first person and third person.
第一人称和第三人称的混合呈现
So in this case, you can see I've got my third-person model over here
所以在这种情况下 你可以看到我的第三人称模型在这里
through this portal.
通过这个入口
Another third person model over here.
另一个第三人称模特在这里
And then we don't see it in the main view because I'm about to turn it on.
然后我们在主视图中看不到它 因为我即将打开它
It would look really weird if you saw the third-person view in the main view.
如果你在主视图中看到第三人称视图 它看起来会非常奇怪
Yeah.
嗯
I mean, some games do try to fix this with very special representations.
我的意思是 一些游戏确实试图用非常特殊的表现来解决这个问题
They'll try to draw just the legs or something like that.
他们会试着只画腿或类似的东西
But, yes, so we have to have a complicated system
但是 是的 所以我们必须有一个复杂的系统
to figure out when to draw third person and when to draw first person.
弄清楚什么时候画第三人称 什么时候画第一人称
And if you were to guess, I bet you would say, well, just
如果你猜的话 我打赌你会说 嗯 只是
render a third person every time you look through a portal.
每次通过门户查看时都渲染第三人
And it turns out it's slightly more complicated than that.
事实证明 情况要比这稍微复杂一些
I'm not actually going to get into the complicated version,
我不会真的进入复杂的版本
but I'm going to show you how it's broken
但我要向你展示它是如何破碎的
if you use that simple rule because why would life be easy
如果你使用这个简单的规则 为什么生活会很容易
and we would just be able to render just when
我们恰好可以在
we're on the other side of a portal.
我们在传送门的另一边
So in this case--
所以在这种情况下--
let me look up.
让我抬起头来
So you'll notice in this case, I'm on a tilted angle.
所以你会注意到 在这种情况下 我是倾斜的
And this is a case where my feet are on one side of the portal
这是一个我的脚在传送门一侧的情况
and my eyes are on the other side of the portal.
我的眼睛在传送门的另一边
So it kind of breaks the original system that
所以它在某种程度上打破了原来的系统
would say, oh, just render if you're on the other side of a portal.
会说 哦 如果你在门户的另一边 只需渲染即可
And so, yeah, it's a little more complicated.
所以 是的 这有点复杂
Not terribly.
不是很严重
It should actually look way more broken than this,
实际上 它看起来应该比这更破碎
but we actually had the fix in several places.
但我们实际上在几个地方找到了解决办法
And this is a special build where I had to go back and break things
这是一个特殊的建筑 我不得不回到过去 打破东西
and only broken it in one place.
只在一个地方把它弄断了
Yeah, OK.
好的 好的
And then the last on our rendering portion.
然后是渲染部分的最后一个
So earlier I had talked about how we need to duplicate
所以早些时候我谈到了我们需要如何复制
geometry that is mid-portal.
位于入口中间的几何图形
But there's also another thing that we need to duplicate,
但还有一件事我们需要复制
which there are screen space affects where we can query
有哪些屏幕空间会影响我们可以查询的位置
draw operations and things like that.
绘制运算之类的东西
And so one way that we use these draw operations that are in screen space
因此 我们使用屏幕空间中的这些绘制操作的一种方式
is to determine how much light glare to use around these lights.
是为了确定在这些灯周围使用多少光眩光
And so how these work are basically we draw a quad
所以这些是如何工作的 基本上我们画了一个四边形
while we're drawing the light.
当我们在拉灯的时候
And then we say, OK, in a couple of frames
然后我们说 好的 在几帧中
I want you to tell me how many pixels actually drew.
我要你告诉我实际绘制了多少像素
And we're not allowed to actually query this immediately because of pipeline
因为管道的关系 我们不能直接查询
reasons.
原因
We don't have the results for several frames.
我们还没有几帧的结果
So we have to cache off that handle that says
所以我们得把那个写着
how many pixels did you draw and we'll get the result at some point later.
你画了多少像素 我们稍后会得到结果
Sometimes you're lucky and it's just one frame, but usually two
有时候你很幸运 只有一帧 但通常是两帧
or three frames-- you have to save it for a while.
或者三帧--你得保存一段时间
But you may notice that even though we're not
但你可能注意到了
replicating the geometry of the light, we're drawing two of them
复制光的几何形状 我们画了两个
because they're in screen space.
因为它们在屏幕上
So that means that this query system had to be smart about it
这意味着这个查询系统必须很聪明
and I'm going to show how we have two separate results.
我将展示两个不同的结果
Now if we had used the engine as it was originally written,
如果我们用的是最初写的引擎
there would be just one query for one light.
对于一个灯只有一个查询
But then that would mean that these lights would dim in unison.
但那就意味着这些灯会同时变暗
So we need to have separate buckets for each view of portals.
因此 我们需要为每个门户视图提供单独的存储桶
And every view query that portal--
每个浏览者查询这个入口
any view query that is issued while in that recursion,
在该递归中发出的任何视图查询
we have to keep it in a totally separate bucket and call it back later.
我们必须把它放在一个完全独立的桶里 然后再把它叫回来
And then as we walk through portals, we have to transfer those buckets.
当我们穿过传送门时 我们必须转移那些桶
So if I were to walk into the blue portal at this point, all of those
所以如果我现在走进蓝色入口
handles we have to transfer to the main view.
我们必须转移到主视图的句柄
And then all the ones that are from the main view we transfer into what was now
然后我们把主视图中的所有图像转换成现在的图像
orange because we would be walking out of this orange one
橙色的 因为我们会走出这个橙色的
if we walked into the blue.
如果我们走进蓝色
So, yeah, that is the quick set of rendering things I wanted to cover.
所以 是的 这就是我想介绍的快速渲染
So now I'm going to hand it off to my colleague, Tejeev,
现在我把它交给我的同事Tejeev
to talk a bit about design.
谈谈设计
Give your spatial thinking a bit of a rest.
让你的空间思维休息一下
[CHUCKLES]
[笑]
TEJEEV KOHLI: So that was a lot of technical stuff
TEJEEV KOHLI：所以这是很多技术性的东西
about rendering of portals.
关于传送门的渲染
And you can see it's more complex than it seems at first.
你可以看到它比一开始看起来更复杂
The naive solution seems like we'll get you most of the way there,
天真的解决方案似乎是我们会让你大部分的方式
but then as you start putting in more things in the game and more ways
但是当你开始在游戏中加入更多的东西和更多的方式
to play a game, to interact with the game,
玩游戏 与游戏互动
you see there's a bunch of different complexities
你看 有一堆不同的复杂性
that you have to account for.
这一点你必须解释清楚
And a lot of those complexities are not just in a technical sense,
这些复杂性中的许多不仅仅是在技术上的
but also from a design sense.
但也是从设计的角度来看
So I just want to talk through some of the issues
所以我只想谈谈其中一些问题
that we came up with as we were making Portal 1 and 2 and some of the ways
这是我们在制作门户1和门户2时想出来的 以及一些方法
we tried to solve them.
我们试图解决这些问题
One of the first things I wanted to mention
我想提的第一件事是
was when first coming up with the idea for portals,
是在第一次提出门户的想法时
before figuring out if we should spend a bunch of time
在弄清楚我们是否应该花一大堆时间
making this idea, this new game mechanic that most people haven't seen before.
想出这个点子 这个大多数人都没见过的新游戏机械师
What we did was--
我们所做的是--
Dave and his team made a prototype of Portal
戴夫和他的团队制作了门户的原型
in a 2D game engine that is used in DigiPen while they were students.
在他们还是学生的时候 DigiPen使用的2D游戏引擎
And it was made in-house DigiPen 2D engine.
它是内部制造的DigiPen 2D引擎
And you can see here that it's a 2D version of Portal,
你可以在这里看到它是门户网站的2D版本
but it's still got all the basic game mechanics that are used in Portal.
但它仍然拥有门户网站中使用的所有基本游戏机制
And the main goal of doing something like this is to vet out the mechanics
这样做的主要目的是为了查清机制
and see if they're still fun at their core.
看看他们的核心是不是仍然有趣
And part of what you do here is you playtest, right?
你在这里做的一部分就是你的游戏测试 对吗？
You make this simple prototype, and you get
你制作这个简单的原型 你就会得到
other people to try it out and play it and say, hey, is this fun?
其他人试着玩 然后说 嘿 这很有趣吗？
Is this something that we should spend our next year working on
这是我们下一年应该做的事情吗？
as a proper 3D game?
作为一款真正的3D游戏？
And the prototype you can see had most of the basic functionality
你可以看到的原型具有大多数基本功能
there and kind of vetted out the idea of the mechanics to take it forward.
在那里 某种程度上审查了机械师的想法 以推动它的发展
And as we take the mechanics forward, one
当我们把机械学向前推进时 一个
of the first things that you realize is this
你首先意识到的一件事是
is a brand new mechanic that people don't really understand
是一种全新的机械师 人们并不真正了解
and you have a train them.
你有一辆火车来训练他们
Train them with how the mechanic works and also
向他们传授机械师的工作原理 还有
train them with sufficient knowledge so they
用足够的知识培训他们 这样他们
can use that mechanic to solve puzzles, which is the core of the game.
可以使用那个机械师来解决谜题 这是游戏的核心
And one of the things that we did is you have
我们做的其中一件事是你有
to have certain sections of the game where
让游戏中的某些部分
you can be sure that the player has the knowledge that they need to progress.
你可以肯定的是 球员知道他们需要进步
So a lot of this is about making sure that the levels you're designing
所以这很大程度上是为了确保你正在设计的关卡
are done in such a way that when the player finishes that level,
以这样的方式完成 当玩家完成该关卡时
they have that knowledge that you want them to have.
他们拥有你想让他们拥有的知识
And one of the ways we ensure that is through doing a lot of play testing,
而我们确保这一点的方法之一是通过做大量的游戏测试
and play testing is something I'll talk about a little more as the talk goes
游戏测试是我将在演讲中更多讨论的内容
on.
在……上面
But the basic idea of play testing is just
但游戏测试的基本理念只是
getting someone else to play the game.
让别人来玩这个游戏
And that someone else could be a coworker
其他人可能是你的同事
who sits next to you, your friend--
他坐在你旁边 你的朋友--
anyone else really.
其他任何人 真的
Someone you get especially to come play the game from outside the company,
你特意从公司外找来玩游戏的人
but usually it's just your coworkers, people that sit next to you.
但通常只有你的同事 坐在你旁边的人
People that see you work on the game but don't know exactly what you're doing.
看到你在游戏上工作但不知道你到底在做什么的人
And you can observe them and see what they're doing,
你可以观察他们 看看他们在做什么
get some feedback from them, and then use that data
从他们那里获得一些反馈 然后使用这些数据
and iterate on the mechanic.
然后重复机械师的话
And you can see here, this was a level in Portal 1.
你可以在这里看到 这是门户1的一个关卡
It was pretty early on, this level, and you could see the portals here.
这是相当早的时候 这个水平 你可以看到这里的门户
The blue portal here is moving on a timer.
这里的蓝色入口正在计时器上移动
It moves from one to the next to the next.
它从一个移动到下一个再到下一个
And the idea of this level was by the time players solve this,
这个水平的想法是 当玩家解决这个问题时
they understand that I go in one portal and come out the other.
他们明白 我从一个入口进去 从另一个入口出来
That's the basic idea here.
这就是这里的基本理念
And in Portal 1, this level did a pretty good job of teaching players that.
而在门户1中 这一关卡在教授玩家这方面做得相当好
For Portal 2, we have a very similar puzzle.
对于门户2 我们有一个非常相似的谜题
I'm going to just try and play here.
我只想试着在这里打球
It's a pretty similar puzzle.
这是一个非常相似的谜题
The idea is the same thing.
这个想法是一样的
You have the three sections that the portal can go.
您有三个门户可以访问的部分
The one change we made here was we move the portal away from a timer
我们在这里所做的一项更改是将门户从计时器移走
and moved it to a button.
然后把它移到一个按钮上
So this way the player has more control of where the portals are opening.
这样玩家就能更好地控制传送门的开启位置
There are a few reasons for this.
这有几个原因
The main one here is like the level in Portal 2 has a lot more visual noise.
这里主要的一个是像在门户2的水平有更多的视觉噪音
There's a lot more like--
还有很多更像...
it's an old level, a lot of foliage, a lot of destroyed stuff.
这是一个旧的水平 很多树叶 很多破坏的东西
So it's not as clean as Portal 1.
所以它不像传送门1那么干净
And also, there's a case of Portal 2, there's
还有一个传送门2的例子
a lot of people that have already played Portal 1
很多已经玩过传送门1的人
and are probably already familiar with the mechanics.
并且可能已经熟悉了机械
So we don't want them to have to go through the timers
所以我们不想让他们通过计时器
and wait for all the things to happen, even though they know how it works.
等着所有的事情发生 即使他们知道它是如何工作的
So this way they can just go in and show us
这样他们就可以直接进去给我们看
that they know how the portals work without having
他们知道传送门是如何工作的
to wait through all the timers.
等完所有的计时器
And the basic goal is the same thing.
基本目标是一样的
That by the end of this level, we're confident that the players understand
在这一关结束时 我们相信玩家们会明白
how portals work.
门户网站是如何运作的
One of the other things that you learn through play testing
你通过游戏测试学到的另一件事
is you learn what you need to teach the player.
就是你学会了你需要教给玩家的东西
There's sometimes when you'll be making the game
有时候你在制作游戏的时候
and there's certain things that you as a designer or as a creator
作为一个设计师或者创作者
won't think are challenging concepts or are things that need
不会认为是具有挑战性的概念 或者是需要
to be talked to players explicitly.
明确地与玩家交谈
One of those things that we noticed early on
我们很早就注意到
is this concept here where a lot of players kind of thought portals
很多玩家认为
were one way.
是一种方式
That you go in one and you come out the other and that's it.
从一个进去从另一个出来就这样
But they have to be taught that you can actually go in both ways.
但他们必须被教导 你实际上可以走两条路
You can go in the blue one and come out the orange,
你可以穿蓝色的衣服出来穿橙色的
or you can go in the orange one and come out the blue one.
或者你可以从橙色的盒子里进去 然后从蓝色的盒子里出来
And so this puzzle specifically does that, where the blue one
所以这个拼图就是这么做的 蓝色的
is the only one that'd be moving.
是唯一会动的
The orange one stays stationary.
橙色的保持不动
First you go in the blue one, you come out the orange one, replace the blue,
你先从蓝色的那个进去 然后从橙色的那个出来 再换掉蓝色的
and then you go in the orange one and come out the blue one.
然后你从橙色的盒子里进去 再从蓝色的盒子里出来
The idea with this again is you have to figure through play testing
这个想法是你必须通过游戏测试来计算
is how you figure out the different things.
就是你如何分辨不同的事物
The different discrete small things that you need to teach the player.
你需要教玩家的不同的离散的小事情
And also try to figure out how to teach them in a way
同时也想办法教他们
where they're figuring it out instead of you telling it to them.
是他们自己想出来的而不是你告诉他们的
So for the most part in Portal 1 and 2, there's
所以在传送门1和2中
certain things that we tell the player.
我们告诉玩家的一些事情
But for the most part we want them to figure it
但在大多数情况下 我们希望他们能理解
out and have that epiphany themselves.
出来自己顿悟
Because then they really learn it.
因为这样他们才真正学会了
If you just tell it to them, they might not take in the exact knowledge.
如果你只是告诉他们 他们可能不会接受确切的知识
Another thing here is this was a level in Portal 2,
另一件事是 这是《传送门2》中的一个关卡
but we noticed through one of our play tests--
但我们通过一个游戏测试注意到--
I looked through a few of our play tests that players were super
我看了一些我们的比赛测试
hesitant to place portals on the floor.
犹豫着要不要把传送门放在地板上
Even though this level is probably the fifth or sixth one in the game,
尽管这个级别可能是游戏中的第五或第六个
and you've done that a few times in the game before this.
在此之前的游戏中你已经这样做过几次了
But usually you are doing it way down there
但通常你都是在下面做
and doing a fling mechanic where you fly through the portal and come out.
做一个飞行机械师 你穿过入口飞出来
So players have placed portal on the floor before,
所以玩家们以前把传送门放在地板上
but they haven't done it right at their feet.
但他们并没有在自己的脚边做
So we had to design a scenario here where the only way forward--
所以我们必须设计一个方案 唯一的出路--
you're trapped in this black room with nothing else
你被困在这间黑屋子里一无所有
and the only thing you can do is place a portal on the floor there.
你唯一能做的就是在地板上放一个传送门
And that's one of the things that you realize as you keep testing.
这是你在不断测试的过程中意识到的事情之一
You'll come across players of different skill levels
你会遇到不同技术水平的球员
and different knowledge of video games and different knowledge
不同的电子游戏知识和不同的知识
of how controls work.
控制是如何工作的
And typically you want to make sure that you're not only catering
通常你要确保你不仅仅是在提供餐饮服务
to the low end or the high end.
到低端或高端
You want to make sure that both of them can have a good time with your game.
你要确保他们两个都能在你的游戏中玩得开心
So you want to design puzzle games in a way that aren't super intrusive.
所以你想设计一种不太打扰人的益智游戏
If a player that sees this get here already
如果一个球员看到这个已经到了这里
knows that I can place portals on floor and go by.
我知道我可以把传送门放在地板上 然后经过
This doesn't seem like anything that's stopping him.
这看起来不像是什么能阻止他的
This just seems like part of the level.
这看起来只是水平的一部分
But to a new player that comes in here and is
但对于一个来到这里的新玩家来说
like I don't know how to proceed, it takes them a while to figure it out.
就像我不知道该怎么做一样 他们需要一段时间才能弄明白
And then when they have that aha moment, they feel pretty smart about it.
然后 当他们有了灵光一现的时刻 他们就会觉得很聪明
So you want to make sure that you're designing stuff
所以你想确保你设计的东西
in a way that isn't frustrating players that already understand the mechanics,
在某种程度上 这并不会让已经了解机制的玩家感到沮丧
but also isn't making players that don't understand the mechanics have
但也不是让不了解机制的球员有
to be super frustrated as well.
也会感到超级沮丧
Another thing that we had to do--
我们不得不做的另一件事是--
Portal 1 and 2 both have this mechanic where you go into a portal on the floor
传送门1和2都有这样的机械师 你可以进入地板上的传送门
and come out one on the wall and it keeps your momentum and velocity
从墙上出来 它会保持你的动量和速度
and flings you forward.
然后把你往前推
One of the things we noticed while we were working on this mechanic
当我们在研究这个机械师时 我们注意到了一件事
is that there's a lot of times when players don't exactly quite line up
很多时候球员并不是完全排成一队
as they're falling through the portal.
当他们从传送门掉下来的时候
Which means that when they fall in, they're going to fall out--
这意味着当他们坠入时 他们将会翻身--
they're not going to come out of the portal on the wall in the correct way.
他们不会以正确的方式从墙上的传送门出来
And a lot of times players won't know that they had the right solution,
很多时候 玩家不知道他们有正确的解决方案
they just kind of messed up the execution a little bit.
他们只是把执行过程搞砸了一点
And we want to try and help the players in these cases,
我们想试着帮助这些案例中的玩家
but again try to be not intrusive about it.
但还是要尽量不要干涉这件事
Because you want to make sure that the players--
因为你想确保球员们--
as they're solving puzzles, they're not thinking
当他们在解谜的时候 他们不会思考
that they had the right solution but it didn't work the first time I tried it.
他们有正确的解决方案 但我第一次尝试时并没有奏效
So now I have to rethink the whole solution even though the solution was
所以现在我不得不重新考虑整个解决方案 尽管解决方案是
correct the first time.
第一次改正
So one of the things we used-- we used a few different things
所以我们使用的其中一个东西--我们使用了一些不同的东西
to help the players out in this way.
以这种方式帮助球员
And again, with the idea of them being mostly invisible to the player.
同样 他们的想法是玩家几乎看不见他们
They're not always completely invisible and in some cases
它们并不总是完全看不见的 在某些情况下
we have ways to opt out of them.
我们有办法选择退出它们
But this is one of the things that we used.
但这是我们用过的东西之一
So if you notice here, the player's going
所以如果你注意到这里 玩家会去
to drop through the orange portal.
穿过橙色的传送门
But as you notice as I walk through--
但正如你注意到的 当我走过的时候--
walk forward here, I'm purposely not going to fall exactly straight.
往前走 我故意不会完全笔直地掉下去
And one of the mechanics we had in the game was--
我们在游戏中的机械师之一是--
it was pretty subtle there, but I'm going to do it again.
这是相当微妙的 但我会再来一次
You'll see I'm walking to the side and the game kind of funnels you
你会看到我走到一边 游戏就像漏斗一样把你
into the portal.
进入传送门
So we had the special thing we used in portals, for portals
所以我们有我们在门户中使用的特殊东西 用于门户
that are on the floor facing mostly up.
大部分是朝上放在地板上的
Imagine there's a cone coming out of the portal,
想象有一个圆锥体从传送门出来
and if you're falling from some height and if you're
如果你从某个高度坠落 如果你
within that cone and the cone--
在那个圆锥体和这个圆锥体内--
it's not super wide.
它不是超宽的
It's pretty narrow.
它很窄
If you're within that cone, then we kind of
如果你在那个圆锥体里 那么我们
funnel you into the center of the portal.
把你引到传送门的中央
So that when you're coming out of it, you're
所以当你走出它的时候 你是
going to be lined up perfectly with it.
会和它完美地排成一排
And as you can see, the third time I did it there, it didn't happen.
正如你所看到的 我第三次在那里做的时候 它没有发生
Because the way this works is that it only
因为它的工作方式是它只
works if you're looking at a portal.
如果你在看传送门的话 这很管用
So it works the second time, but the third time I'm
所以它第二次起作用了 但第三次我
going to go mostly in the same direction and it's not going to work.
大体上都是朝同一个方向前进 这是行不通的
So that's our way of trying to make these things be non-intrusive.
所以这就是我们试图让这些东西成为非侵入性的方式
To where if players don't expect to go in that portal, it's not going to work.
如果玩家不希望进入那个门户 它就不会起作用
But if the player is looking at a portal and they expect to go in it,
但如果玩家正在寻找一个门户 他们希望进入其中
we kind of nudge them along a little bit.
我们有点像是在推动他们前进
And you can see it here, and this is a second case
你可以在这里看到 这是第二个案例
of the same thing where there's a portal on the floor and the ceiling.
同样的东西 地板和天花板上都有一个入口
And you can see as the funnel is working,
你可以看到漏斗在工作
the play is perfectly in the center of it.
这出戏恰如其分地处于中心位置
But I'm going to look forward a little bit and disable the funnel.
但我会往前看一看 关闭漏斗
And you can see the player's going to go off axis
你可以看到玩家会偏离轴心
because the funnels are disabled and the player slowly went out of it.
因为漏斗被禁用了 球员慢慢地走出了漏斗
Yeah, the funnel is disabled now.
是啊 漏斗现在失灵了
And again, the idea of this is to reduce a bunch of the player frustration
再说一次 这个想法是为了减少玩家的挫折感
and to reduce a bunch of the false negatives that players get.
以减少玩家得到的一大堆假阴性
You want to make sure that players that think they've got the solution,
你想确保那些认为他们有解决方案的玩家
and if it was the correct solution, you want
如果这是正确的解决方案 你想
to kind of help them out a little bit.
想帮他们一点忙
You don't to solve the puzzle for them.
你不需要为他们解开谜题
You don't want to give them, like, here's the answer.
你不会想给他们 比如 这就是答案
But you do want to try and help them out a little bit
但你确实想试着帮他们一点忙
because that helps that makes the game a little bit more fun
因为这有助于让游戏更有趣一些
and reduces the frustration.
并减少挫折感
So that was the help that we had for when you're entering portals.
这就是我们在进入传送门时得到的帮助
We also have the opposite and that was there in Portal 1.
我们也有相反的东西 那就是在1号门户
And in Portal 2, we introduced something that
在门户2中 我们介绍了一些
was the opposite of a helper, which we used when you're coming out of portals.
是帮手的对立面 当你走出大门时 我们会用到帮手
So Portal 2 had this mechanic called Aerial Faith Plates,
所以2号传送门有一名机械师 叫空中信仰牌
which is pretty straightforward.
这很简单
You step on this faith plate and it propels you to the air.
你踩上这个信念盘子 它就会把你推向空中
And the level designers can place the faith plate on a level
关卡设计者可以将信仰牌放在关卡上
and can kind of control the trajectory of the arc
可以控制弧线的轨迹
of where the player is going to fly.
玩家将飞向何处
And this arc is not really visible to the player,
而这条弧线对玩家来说并不是真正可见的
but it's pretty apparent based on the level design.
但根据关卡的设计 这是相当明显的
So you can see in this one, I'm going to play the video as I'm talking
大家可以看到 在这个视频中 我将边讲边播放视频
and then maybe play it a couple of times.
然后可能会播放几次
So the tech that was developed for these Aerial Faith Plates
因此 为这些航空信仰号牌开发的技术
is something that we reuse for a fling helper.
是我们重复使用的玩耍帮手的东西
So you can see here there's all these--
所以你可以看到这里有所有这些--
I'm going to turn on some debug draw.
我要打开一些调试绘图
And you can see right here.
你可以在这里看到
So this green arc here is the arc that's on the faith plates,
这条绿色的弧线就是信仰板块上的弧线
but you can see there's some stuff coming out of the walls there as well.
但你也可以看到有一些东西从那里的墙里出来
So this is a part of the level where the player is going to fling out of.
所以这是水平的一部分 玩家将在那里抛出
He's going to fling a box out of that actually because he wanted this to work
他要扔出一个盒子 实际上是因为他想让它起作用
for objects as well as the player.
对于物体和玩家来说都是如此
So you can see as the box goes through here
所以你可以看到盒子从这里经过
and then here, these are those faith plates.
然后在这里 这些是那些信仰的车牌
And then when the box comes out of that, we
然后当盒子从盒子里出来时 我们
have the box follow the arc that's kind of predetermined.
让长方体沿着预定的弧线移动
Because that's I think what the player is expecting at that point.
因为我认为这是球员在这一点上所期待的
They expected to have solved the solution-- solve the puzzle.
他们本以为已经解决了问题的答案--解决了这个难题
But the funnel, the trigger here--
但是漏斗 这里的导火索--
this kind of corrects the arc to make sure that it's always going
这样可以纠正弧线 以确保它始终在运行
to go in the place the player expects.
去球员期望的地方
And we also have a case of the same things working for the player.
我们也有同样的事情在球员身上发挥作用
So you can see here there's two different arcs that
所以你可以看到这里有两条不同的弧线
are coming out because we doubled up the triggers over here.
是因为我们在这里加倍了扳机
The way these triggers worked in the game
这些触发器在游戏中的工作方式
is they won't always enable when the player touches them.
当玩家触摸它们时 它们并不总是启用
They require a minimum velocity threshold.
它们需要一个最小速度阈值
So the player has to be doing most of the work.
所以玩家必须做大部分的工作
So the player has to have figured out a way in the level
所以玩家一定已经想出了一种方法
through the puzzle design to get that velocity.
通过拼图设计得到那个速度
But we know that there's some differences in physics and differences
但我们知道在物理学上有一些差异和差异
in the exact mechanism you might use.
在你可能使用的确切机制中
So we're just saying if you got the minimum velocity that we acquire,
所以我们只是说 如果你得到了我们所获得的最小速度
we're going to take it all the way there.
我们要把它一直带到那里
So in this one, you can see we have two different cases.
所以在这个例子中 你可以看到我们有两个不同的案例
So if I just fall out of the portal, it's not going to activate any of them.
所以如果我只是从传送门掉出来 它不会激活它们中的任何一个
If I somehow manage to get some velocity,
如果我设法获得了一些速度
is going to activate the fail case one and take me there.
将启动失败案例一并将我带到那里
And the reason we have the fail case one is
我们有失败案例一的原因是
because we want to make sure that if players somehow get
因为我们想确保如果玩家以某种方式
most of the velocity but bonk on the wall,
大部分的速度都撞在墙上了
they don't keep thinking that they can-- that's the correct way to do it.
他们不会一直认为他们可以--这才是正确的做法
So we want to make it obvious that you failed.
所以我们想让大家都知道你失败了
So again it's the same way.
所以这又是同样的方式
We have to help-- you're helping the players out but not by giving them
我们必须帮助--你是在帮助球员 而不是通过给他们
the solution.
解决方案
Just by making it obvious that the thing you did was correct or wrong.
仅仅是通过明确你所做的事情是正确的还是错误的
And then if you do the correct way in this level, which
然后 如果你在这个层次上做了正确的事情
is to get philosophy doing that, and then you make a portal there,
就是让哲学做到这一点 然后你在那里建立一个门户
you're going to do the correct thing and swing out of it.
你要做正确的事情 然后摆脱它
And again, the main idea here is to get rid of those false negatives.
再说一次 这里的主要想法是消除这些假阴性
Especially here because there's a few different spots on the wall
尤其是在这里 因为墙上有几个不同的地方
that you can put a portal.
你可以把一个传送门
And we don't really want to restrict a lot of that
我们真的不想限制很多这样的事情
and just put the one square on the wall.
然后把一个正方形放在墙上
That is the solution square.
这就是解决方案的正方形
Because again, if you put the portal down here or put the portal up here,
因为同样 如果你把传送门放在这里 或者把传送门放在这里
the arc is going to be slightly different.
弧线将会略有不同
So this mechanism we had just kind of corrects
所以这个机制 我们只是在某种程度上纠正
those arcs and makes sure that it goes in the one or two ways that we want.
这些弧线 并确保它以我们想要的一到两种方式进行
Another thing we added in--
我们加入的另一件事是--
this we added in Portal 2--
这是我们在门户2中添加的--
was highlights for your portals so you can see where
是门户的亮点 这样您就可以看到
your portals are placed through walls.
你的传送门是通过墙壁放置的
And this is something that's super useful in levels
这是一个在关卡中非常有用的东西
where you have to keep track of which portal you placed over there.
在那里你必须记录你放在那里的传送门
So you know which one to place over here.
所以你知道该把哪一个放在这里
Because sometimes it's like, OK, I just got out of the blue one
因为有时候就像 好吧 我刚从蓝色的地方出来
and the orange one's over there.
橙色的在那边
So if I place the blue one--
所以如果我把蓝色的--
oh, I got to do the whole puzzle again now because I placed the wrong one.
哦 我现在得把整个拼图再做一遍 因为我把拼图放错了
So this helps a lot in just making sure that you know where your portals are
因此 这对确保您知道门户在哪里有很大帮助
so you can be like I want to come out of that one,
所以你可以表现得像我想走出这一步
so I'm going to place the other one.
所以我要把另一个放在
And this is something we added in Portal 2 and it was pretty helpful.
这是我们在门户2中添加的东西 它非常有帮助
And it's also helpful in the co-op version of the game.
在合作版本的游戏中 这也是有帮助的
Because in the co-op one, you want to see
因为在合作公寓里 你想看到
where both the players' portals are at all times
两个玩家的门户一直都在那里
and this kind mechanic helps in that.
这种机械师在这方面起到了帮助作用
Another thing we added to kind of help the player a little bit
我们增加的另一件事对球员有一点帮助
is a thing we call the placement helper.
是一种我们称之为安置助手的东西
And this does not use a whole lot in the game,
而这在游戏中并没有用到很多东西
but there's a few sections in the game where
但在游戏中有几个部分
we want to encourage the players to come out
我们想鼓励球员们站出来
of a portal in a particular direction.
在特定方向上的入口
So we have these things that we place in the level with a certain radius.
所以我们有这些东西 我们放置在一定半径的水平上
And if you place a portal within that radius,
如果你把传送门放在这个半径内
we just kind of snap it to the direction--
我们只是把它按到那个方向--
to the center of it.
到了它的中心
But they don't a timer.
但他们没有计时器
So if you place one portal and you're like,
所以 如果你放置一个传送门 你会说
oh, I actually want to place it over here, you can always opt out of it.
哦 实际上我想把它放在这里 你可以随时选择不放
And that's again what I was talking earlier.
这也是我之前所说的
You want to add something-- excuse me.
你想补充什么--打扰一下
You want to add these helpers in a way that, for players, they're mostly
你想要添加这些助手的方式是 对于玩家来说 他们主要是
invisible to most of the players.
对大多数玩家来说是隐形的
But the players that want to opt out of them have a way of opting out of them.
但想要退出的球员有办法选择退出
[COUGHS]
[咳嗽声]
Excuse me.
打扰了
So you can see the first portal that's placed does get snapped,
所以你可以看到放置的第一个门户确实被截断了
but the second one that's placed is exactly where the player wanted.
但第二个被放置的正是玩家想要的位置
And we use these in a few spots in the game,
我们在游戏中的一些地方使用了这些
but they weren't used a whole lot because for the most part
但它们并没有被大量使用 因为在大多数情况下
you want to have-- you want to make sure the player feels
你想要--你想确保球员感觉到
like they're in control.
就像他们控制了局面一样
And one of the other things that was a lot of fun
还有一件很有趣的事
while making Portal, and Dave will talk a lot about this--
在制作门户网站时 戴夫会对此大谈特谈--
excuse me-- will talk a lot about this later is the physics of portals,
打扰一下--稍后我会讲到很多关于门户的物理学
or physics of objects interacting with portals.
或物体与门户相互作用的物理学
And for the most part we're trying to be super accurate with it, right?
在大多数情况下 我们都在努力做到超级准确 对吗？
We're trying to make stuff work the way players expect in real life
我们正在努力让东西按照玩家在现实生活中期望的方式工作
because that's kind of what we're trying to simulate here.
因为这就是我们试图在这里模拟的
But one of the things that we thought that we added here-- that we thought
但我们认为我们在这里添加的一件事--我们认为
was more fun than accurate.
与其说准确 不如说有趣
So you can see the--
所以你可以看到--
[COUGHING]
[咳嗽]
Sorry, I'm a little bit sick.
对不起 我有点不舒服
You can see here that when the box starts off,
你可以在这里看到 当盒子启动时
it's just resting on the floor.
它就躺在地板上
So it's got no initial velocity whatsoever.
所以它没有任何初始速度
So when you place the blue portal down, the expectation
所以当你把蓝色的传送门放下来时 期望
is probably that it keeps resting there or maybe it
可能是它一直停留在那里 或者可能是
goes in the center of the portal and just stands there.
走到入口的中央 就站在那里
But that's not a super fun game mechanic.
但这并不是一个超级有趣的游戏机械师
So here we just have it be so that objects coming out of portals
所以在这里 我们只需要让物体从入口出来
have some minimum velocity.
有一些最小的速度
So they always have some minimum velocity.
所以它们总是有一些最小的速度
And this works in lots of other parts of the game like the paint.
这在游戏的许多其他部分都有效 比如油漆
And you can see here that there is some air
你可以看到这里有一些空气
resistance that takes place and the paint does slowly come down.
阻力会发生 油漆会慢慢下降
But once it comes down to this minimum velocity, it just stays there.
但一旦它降到这个最小速度 它就会停留在那里
And this is-- it's like completely fabricated fiction.
而这是--这就像是完全捏造的小说
I guess there's no real physics for this.
我想这并不是真正的物理学
It's just kind of like this is more fun than trying to simulate real physics.
这就像是这样比试图模拟真实的物理更有趣
So you can see here air resistance is making
所以你可以看到这里的空气阻力
it go down, like they're slowing down.
它会下降 就像他们在减速一样
But once they get to the minimum velocity, they just stay there.
但一旦它们达到最小速度 它们就会一直呆在那里
This is about it.
就是这么回事
So once it gets here, it's just going to stay here.
所以 一旦它到了这里 它就会留在这里
It's not going to go below that.
它不会低于这个水平
And speaking of gels, the gels actually came up--
说到凝胶 凝胶实际上出现了--
were an idea that we had for our student game
是我们为学生游戏想出的一个点子
that we made while we were in DigiPen.
这是我们在DigiPen时做的
It was called "Tag--
它被称为“标签--
The Power of Paint."
“绘画的力量 ”
And in Tag, you had a paint gun that you used to shoot the different colors.
在TAG中 你有一把喷漆枪 你用它来拍摄不同的颜色
And the Portal 2 mechanic was adapted from this and it's pretty similar.
传送门2的机械师就是从这个改编而来的 非常相似
But one of the things we did get rid of for Portal 2
但我们为门户2去掉的一件事是
was the idea of having the paint gun.
就是拥有喷漆枪的想法
Because one of the core ideas we had while working on Portal 2
因为我们在门户2上工作时的核心想法之一
was that any mechanics we add to the game should really work with portals
我们添加到游戏中的任何机制都应该真正与门户网站一起工作
and should really interact at a core level with portals.
而且应该真正与门户网站进行核心层面的互动
So we thought instead of using a gun to move the paint around,
所以我们想 与其用枪来移动油漆
it will made much more sense to use the portals to move the paint around.
使用入口来移动油漆会更有意义
And that was kind of core not just with the gels, but with any new mechanic
这不仅是凝胶的核心 也是任何新机械师的核心
we added to the game.
我们增加了比赛的内容
Was that portals is the core idea of the games.
门户是奥运会的核心理念
Everything we do should kind of center around how portals work.
我们所做的一切都应该以门户的工作方式为中心
I'm just showing you the different colors we had in Tag.
我只是向你展示了我们在TAG中的不同颜色
One of the colors that we added in Portal that wasn't there in Tag
我们在门户中添加的其中一种颜色不在标签中
was the portal gel.
是门脉凝胶
And this was again going with the idea of how
这又一次伴随着这样一个想法
do we make the gels and the portals interact better.
我们是否能让凝胶和门户之间的互动更好
So this one just lets you spread around white paint
所以这个只是让你在白色油漆周围涂抹
so you can put portals anywhere that the paint can go.
所以你可以把入口放在油漆可以到达的任何地方
And this is a pretty cool mechanic in that
这是一个相当酷的机械师
it allows for a lot more open-ended level design and a lot more player
它允许更多的开放式关卡设计和更多的玩家
freedom.
自由
Because you can play portals essentially anywhere now.
因为你现在基本上可以在任何地方玩门户网站
Because for a lot of the game we're restricting
因为在很多比赛中我们限制了
where the players can put portals on the black surface or the white surface.
玩家可以在黑色表面或白色表面上放置入口
And this just allows--
而这只是允许--
you can just put white anywhere and put portals anywhere.
你可以把白色放在任何地方 把门户放在任何地方
We didn't use this a whole lot because it is pretty open-ended
我们没有经常使用它 因为它是相当开放的
and it does break a lot of puzzle designs.
它确实打破了许多谜题设计
But there are a few cases where we use it in a pretty open-ended way
但在一些情况下 我们以一种相当开放的方式使用它
and have the player just kind of have fun.
让球员玩得开心一点
Spend some time painting the whole level and then figuring out what to do.
花一些时间来粉刷整个关卡 然后弄清楚该怎么做
And these kind of levels usually have a couple of different solutions
这类级别通常有几种不同的解决方案
because we don't know where the players are going to paint.
因为我们不知道球员们将在哪里作画
So we just put a bunch of different ways to get to the exit and players.
所以我们只是放了一堆不同的方式去出口和球员
Some players figure out all the knobs.
一些玩家弄清楚了所有的旋钮
Some players find the first one and just go there.
有些球员找到了第一个 然后就去了那里
And it helps to break up the pacing a little bit from the conventional puzzle
它有助于打破传统谜题中的节奏
design with the specific spots where here are some white spots, here
用特定的斑点设计 这里是一些白点 这里
are some black spots.
是一些黑点
So it helps break that up a little bit.
因此 这有助于在一定程度上打破这种局面
One of the things that didn't make it through from our student game
我们的学生游戏中有一件事没有通过
was the sticky gel that you saw in the student version.
就是你在学生版中看到的粘性凝胶
So this is going to look a little bit broken
所以这看起来会有点破损
because this is from a really old version of Portal 2
因为这是来自一个非常老的版本的门户2
because the sticky gel got cut pretty early on.
因为粘性凝胶很早就被剪断了
And you're going to see some stuff here that doesn't really
你会在这里看到一些并不是真的
make sense, but just go with it.
这是有道理的 但要顺其自然
So you can see we used purple instead of blue here.
所以你可以看到我们这里用紫色而不是蓝色
So you can jump on-- you can walk on walls and stuff, which is pretty cool.
所以你可以跳上去--你可以走在墙上之类的东西上 这很酷
So here you can see there's blue paint coming out of there
所以你可以看到蓝色的油漆从这里冒出来
but you can't see the actual paint blobs because there
但你看不到实际的油漆斑点 因为
are invisible for some reason.
出于某种原因是看不见的
I couldn't figure it out.
我想不通了
But you can see the actual paint on the walls, on the floor.
但你可以看到墙上和地板上的实际油漆
So this is just an idea of the kind of puzzles
所以这只是一种拼图的想法
we were trying to come up with using sticky paint.
我们试图想出使用粘性油漆的方法
There's an extra portal there for some reason.
出于某种原因 那里有一个额外的入口
Ignore it.
别理它
This is a really old version of the game.
这是这个游戏的一个非常老的版本
So this is the kind of puzzles we are trying to come up with.
所以这就是我们想要解决的谜题
Of combining the different paint colors and portals together.
将不同的油漆颜色和入口结合在一起
But we did end up cutting this feature though.
但我们最终还是删掉了这一功能
There were a few different reasons.
有几个不同的原因
One of them was obviously it is quite disorienting.
其中之一显然是相当令人迷惑的
You can see going up a wall and trying to figure out where
你可以看到爬上一堵墙 试着找出
the ceiling is, where the floor is.
天花板在哪里 地板在哪里
Especially in a lot of these levels where
尤其是在很多这样的层次上
they're mostly just black and white.
它们大多是黑白的
It gets pretty disorienting and we had more than a few play
它变得相当令人迷惑 我们玩了很多次
testers complain about that.
测试人员对此颇有微词
But the other big reason that we cut it is because it didn't really
但我们砍掉它的另一个重要原因是 它并没有真正
interact well with portals.
与门户网站进行良好的互动
You don't really want to walk into a level
你不会真的想走进一个
and have the pots already placed for you.
并且已经为你准备好了花盆
And there's no real good way to make pots on the entire wall
而且没有真正好的方法在整面墙上制作花盆
without having to place the portal like 50 times.
而不需要放置50次传送门
And also it didn't really interact well with the portal player
而且它与门户播放器的交互也不是很好
physics and portal physics, and Dave will talk some more about the player
物理和门户物理 戴夫将谈论更多关于球员的事情
physics through portals.
通过传送门的物理
And this is one of the things that you can see.
这是你可以看到的其中一件事
We had a paint gun for a little bit, but we ended up cutting it.
我们有一把喷漆枪 但最后我们把它剪断了
So you can see I'm painting the wall over here
所以你可以看到我正在粉刷这里的墙
and I'm going to walk on the wall.
我要走在墙上
But as I enter the blue portal, you can see oh, it's
但当我进入蓝色入口时 你可以看到哦 它是
not going to let me go through.
不会让我通过的
But if I go through this way, it works.
但如果我用这种方式 它会起作用的
And that's just one of the things that's like, well, we've got to solve this.
这只是其中一件事 好吧 我们必须解决这个问题
We've got to ship like this.
我们必须像这样装船
We've got to solve the problems.
我们必须解决这些问题
And we spent some time trying to work on these issues.
我们花了一些时间试图解决这些问题
But at some point, you realize that you're not
但在某一时刻 你会意识到你并不是
guaranteed to solve these problems no matter how long you spend on them.
无论你在这些问题上花费多长时间 都能保证解决它们
So at some point you've got to just be like, OK,
所以在某种程度上 你得像这样 好吧
I don't want to spend an extra month or two
我不想多花一两个月的时间
trying to fix these problems not knowing if you'll get there.
试图解决这些问题 不知道你是否能做到这一点
And plus there's other reasons why the mechanic isn't working out.
此外 还有其他原因导致机械师不能工作
So let's just stop working on this and work on other stuff instead.
所以 让我们停止这方面的工作 转而做其他事情
Another thing we ended up cutting--
我们最后砍掉的另一样东西--
this is from Portal 1 that was present in Narbacular Drop was the ability
这是从1号门传来的 当时在纳巴卡拉空投是一种能力
to place portals through portals.
通过门户放置门户
And it's a pretty confusing thing and that
这是一件非常令人困惑的事情
was the main reason we cut it because most players just
是我们取消比赛的主要原因 因为大多数球员只是
thought it was way too confusing.
我觉得这太让人困惑了
Because you're placing the blue portal by looking through the orange
因为你是通过看橙色来放置蓝色入口的
portal here.
传送门在这里
So the blue portal is--
所以蓝色的入口是--
he's pointing through the orange portal here and facing the blue portal over
他指着这里的橙色传送门和那边的蓝色传送门
here because the other blue portal is behind them.
这里是因为另一个蓝色的入口在他们后面
It's just like-- it's too confusing.
就像--这太令人困惑了
And also it doesn't--
而且它也不是--
there's not a lot of puzzle design that you lose by disabling this feature.
禁用这一功能并不会让你失去太多的拼图设计
The thing you do gain is players aren't getting super confused
你得到的好处是玩家不会感到超级困惑
and also you're not necessarily cutting a bunch of puzzles
而且你也不一定要剪下一堆拼图
that you can't make now.
你现在做不到的事
So this feature got cut as well.
因此 这个功能也被删减了
And this is something that we didn't really cut,
这是我们并没有真正删减的东西
but we stopped using in Portal 2 that was used a little bit in Portal 1
但我们停止了在门户2中使用在门户1中使用的一些内容
was the idea of a double fling.
是两次放纵的想法
And I'm going to show it here.
我将在这里展示它
So double fling is basically placing a portal
所以两次放飞基本上就是把一个传送门
while you're falling out of a portal.
当你从传送门上掉下来的时候
And it's one of those things that it works pretty well.
它是其中一种运行得很好的东西
It's a pretty cool mechanic.
这是个很酷的机械师
And it was used in a few spots in Portal 1.
它还在1号门的几个地方使用过
A couple of puzzles required it, like this puzzle here required you
有几个拼图需要它 就像这里的拼图需要你
to do this double fling.
来做这双倍的放纵
But one of the things we noticed was a lot of players
但我们注意到的一件事是有很多玩家
have difficulty in executing a lot of these super hyper-sized,
很难执行很多这样的超大尺寸
high-precision movements even though they know
高精度的动作 即使他们知道
what the solution of the puzzle is.
这个谜题的解决方案是什么
So players will walk in this room and figure out, OK, I've got to do this,
所以玩家走进这个房间 会想 好吧 我必须这么做
I've got to do that, and this is going to work.
我必须这么做 这会奏效的
But then a lot of players have trouble walking out of a portal,
但是很多玩家在走出入口时会遇到困难
making a portal as quickly, and it adds a lot of stress.
以同样快的速度制作门户 会增加很大的压力
And we wanted to move away from a lot of the twitch movement based stuff
我们想要摆脱很多基于抽搐运动的东西
and towards more of a kind of, aha, I got it.
更像是 啊哈 我明白了
That kind of stuff.
诸如此类的东西
And once you get it, we don't want you to spend a bunch of time
一旦你拿到了 我们不想让你花很多时间
in making sure you get the precise movements right.
确保你的动作准确无误
So this feature we didn't really cut it.
所以这个功能我们并没有真正删减
It's still a mechanic that works in Portal 2,
它仍然是在2号传送门工作的机械师
but none of the puzzles in Portal 2 required it anymore.
但门户2中的谜题都不再需要它了
And once we added the level editor, a lot of the puzzles people
一旦我们添加了关卡编辑器 很多玩拼图的人
are making do require it and a lot of players like it.
确实需要这样做 很多球员都喜欢这样
But it's not something that we thought we wanted to make everyone have to do.
但这并不是我们认为我们想让每个人都必须做的事情
Another thing that we changed from Portal 1 to Portal 2
我们将门户1更改为门户2的另一件事
was these energy balls.
就是这些能量球
These energy balls at the time--
这些能量球在当时--
part of the reason we used them in Portal 1
我们在门户1中使用它们的部分原因
was because they were there in Half-Life and it
是因为他们在《半条命》里
was an already created mechanic that we had that we could just keep from them.
是一个我们已经创造出来的机械师 我们可以不让他们知道
But the basic mechanic is these things fire--
但基本的机械原理是这些东西会起火--
these things fire this ball that bounces around
这些东西发射这个弹跳的球
and it needs to go in this receptacle here under my gun right now.
现在就得把它放到我枪下的这个容器里
And it should go in this receptacle here and once it goes there,
它应该放在这个容器里 一旦放到那里
it finishes the puzzle.
它完成了拼图
There are a few issues with this mechanic, though,
不过 这位机械师有一些问题
in that there's a bunch of timing element involved here.
这其中涉及到一系列的计时因素
Because the ball takes time to travel.
因为球的移动需要时间
And also if you get hit by it, you die.
如果你被它击中 你也会死
Which, I mean, it's fine.
我是说 这很好
It's a game mechanic
这是个游戏机械师
But for Portal 2, we just thought, how can we improve on this idea?
但对于门户2 我们只是在想 我们如何才能改进这个想法？
And the thing we came up with was using lasers instead of the energy balls.
我们想出的办法是用激光代替能量球
Lower the volume a little bit.
把音量调低一点
So here you can see it it's the same level from Portal 1
所以你可以在这里看到它 它与1号门的高度相同
and you can even see the energy ball dispenser going away and being replaced
你甚至可以看到能量球分配器被取代了
by a laser because we want to make sure the player is
因为我们要确保玩家是
like, GLaDOS is improving these mechanics now
比如 GLaDOS现在正在改进这些机制
and got better versions of it.
并得到了更好的版本
So the laser effectively is very similar to the energy ball.
所以激光实际上非常类似于能量球
It goes in one and you want it--
它放在一个里面 你想要它--
it goes in over here and you want it to go to the receptacle over there.
它进入这里 你想让它进入那边的容器
The big advantage here is that the reaction is instant.
这里的最大优势是 反应是即时的
So if the player got the solution or not, it's instantaneous.
因此 无论玩家是否得到了解决方案 它都是瞬间的
You don't have to have situations where you place the exit portal
您不必在放置出口入口的情况下
and now you have to wait for the ball to go all the way across the level
现在你必须等待球穿过关卡
and see if it lines up or not.
看看它是否对齐了
This way it just instantly does it.
这样一来 它立刻就能做到这一点
Plus it also opens up a bunch of different game play opportunities
此外 它还打开了一系列不同的游戏机会
because now you can use multiple relays in the same level.
因为现在您可以在同一级别使用多个继电器
You can have the cube that redirects the laser.
你可以得到重定向激光的立方体
So overall it felt like an improvement over the energy ball.
因此 总的来说 这感觉像是对能量球的改进
And talking about lasers, so far we've been
谈到激光 到目前为止 我们已经
talking about a bunch of these smaller decisions we've
谈论一大堆我们已经做出的小决定
made to solve these smaller problems as they kept coming up, like entering
是为了解决这些不断出现的小问题 比如进入
exiting portals, making sure things are lined up or not,
从传送门出来 确保东西都排好了
improving on the specific game mechanics.
改进了具体的游戏机制
But one of the things that you need to do
但你需要做的一件事是
when you're trying to make a whole game is
当你试图让一场比赛变得完整
to see how these mechanics come together and how you can combine them together
了解这些机制是如何结合在一起的 以及如何将它们结合在一起
to make a whole game.
才能做出一场完整的比赛
To make a few puzzles that increase into difficulty, complexity,
做一些增加难度、复杂性的谜题
and go towards some crescendo.
然后走向某种高潮
And one of the ways we did that is by kind of using this kind of process
我们做到这一点的方法之一是使用这种过程
that I'm going to go through.
我要经历的一切
And we used it a couple of times both in Portal 1 and in Portal 2.
我们在门户1和门户2中都使用过它几次
And there's a few different mechanics that we used the cycle over and over
有几种不同的机制 我们反复使用这个循环
for.
为
And that's kind of how the entire game track is designed.
这就是整个游戏赛道的设计方式
So it starts off with an introduction, and the introduction
所以这是从介绍开始的 介绍
is the puzzle we just showed you.
就是我们刚刚给你看的那个拼图
That's the intro puzzle for lasers and it's really straightforward.
这就是激光的入门难题 而且非常简单
It just shows you the mechanic.
它只是向你展示了机械师
You go through one portal, come out the other, goes into the receptacle.
你穿过一扇门 从另一扇门出来 进入容器
It's really straightforward.
这真的很简单
Introduces the mechanic.
介绍机械师
Most people would get tripped up on this.
大多数人都会在这件事上被绊倒
From there, we then try to saturate the player with that same mechanic.
然后 我们试着用同样的机械师让玩家饱和
We introduce different twists on that same--
我们在这一点上引入了不同的曲折--
without introducing a whole new mechanic,
如果不介绍一位全新的技师
we just introduce different versions, different tweaks on that same idea.
我们只是推出了不同的版本 对同一想法进行了不同的调整
So this room still only has lasers.
所以这个房间里仍然只有激光
But now we've introduced relays and cubes.
但现在我们引入了继电器和立方体
And you can experiment, figure out how to connect the three lasers together.
你可以进行实验 弄清楚如何将三个激光连接在一起
Figure out how to move the cube, figure out
弄清楚如何移动立方体 弄清楚
how to move the laser through the portals.
如何让激光穿过传送门
But still it's only lasers.
但它仍然只是激光
Nothing super complex yet.
目前还没有什么超级复杂的东西
Then we give you more of that.
然后我们会给你更多这样的东西
We give you more of just the same mechanic.
我们为您提供更多相同的机械师
Here there's two things firing lasers and two things you've got to connect.
这里有两个发射激光的东西 还有两个你必须联系起来的东西
And so it's the same idea.
所以这是同样的想法
It's like just using lasers, but not super complex.
这就像只是使用激光 但不是非常复杂
Just building on the complexity little by little.
只是在一点一点地建立在复杂性的基础上
Followed by a puzzle that's like, OK, this
然后是一个拼图 就像 好的 这个
is a puzzle that's going to teach you all about lasers.
是一个谜题 它将教你关于激光的一切
By now you've seen lasers in a few different ways.
到目前为止 你已经以几种不同的方式看到了激光
This one, once you get this, you understand how lasers work.
这个 一旦你得到这个 你就会明白激光是如何工作的
You know everything there is to know about how lasers work.
你知道关于激光工作原理的一切
So this puzzle here--
所以这里的谜题--
excuse me-- that's two cubes and three things firing lasers,
打扰一下--这是两个立方体和三个发射激光的东西
and on the other side of the puzzle there's
在拼图的另一边 有
three things-- you've got to connect them.
三件事--你必须把它们联系起来
And this puzzle is very difficult, but by this point,
这个谜题很难 但到了这一步
you've been slowly introduced to different ideas
你被慢慢地介绍给不同的想法
of how lasers work and this one is taking them all together.
激光是如何工作的 而这一次是将它们结合在一起
And then once we've done that, then we start combining them.
一旦我们做到了这一点 我们就开始把它们结合起来
Then we start taking, OK, now you've got a laser
然后我们开始拍摄 好的 现在你有了激光
and a different cube and a bridge.
一个不同的立方体和一座桥
And by this point you've seen a whole separate--
在这一点上 你已经看到了一个完全不同的--
we've done the whole introduction, saturation, graduation track
我们已经完成了整个入门、饱和、毕业跟踪
with bridges as well.
桥梁也是如此
So by this point, you go in there and, OK, I
所以到了这一步 你走进去 好的 我
know how bridges, I know how lasers work.
我知道桥梁是怎么回事 我知道激光是怎么工作的
How do they work together?
它们如何协同工作？
How do I combine them together?
我如何将它们组合在一起？
And then we start escalating from there.
然后我们从那里开始升级
And then you go into this puzzle that has a bridge, has a laser,
然后你进入这个有桥 有激光的拼图
has a turret, has some cubes coming out, has a catapult,
有一个炮塔 有一些立方体出来 有一个弹射器
has a bunch of this stuff.
有一大堆这样的东西
But by the time the player gets here, they're
但当玩家赶到的时候 他们已经
not really overwhelmed by it because they
并不是真的不知所措 因为他们
have been introduced to all these mechanics separately and also
已经分别介绍了所有这些机械原理 而且
smaller combinations of them.
它们的较小组合
So that when they get to this point where
所以当他们到达这一点时
there's a bunch of different mechanics, they
有一堆不同的机制 他们
know how they all work individually.
了解它们各自是如何工作的
And that's kind of the process that we use of slowly ramping up
这就是我们使用的一种缓慢提升的过程
the difficulty, first with a single mechanic, then combining them.
难度 首先是单一的机械师 然后将它们结合起来
And then that's kind of how we take the individual smaller design elements
然后这就是我们如何将单个较小的设计元素
and combine them together and turn them into the whole game.
然后把它们结合在一起 把它们变成整个游戏
And now I think Dave is going to come back and talk some more about physics.
现在 我想戴夫会回来 谈论更多关于物理学的话题
DAVE KIRCHER: And after I cover these last four bits of physics,
戴夫·科尔彻：在我讲完这最后四个物理学知识之后
we're going to open up for questions.
我们现在开始接受提问
I know we have a whole miscellaneous section that we've outlined here,
我知道我们在这里概述了一整节杂乱的内容
but that's more just buffer material.
但这更多的只是缓冲材料
So I'm hoping you're going to put your spatial thinking caps back on.
所以我希望你能重新开始你的空间思维
So how we handle portal transitions is there's two distinct methods.
因此 我们处理门户过渡的方式是有两种不同的方法
One is that we've got volumes here, which we call touch volumes or trigger
一个是我们这里有音量 我们称之为触摸音量或触发器
volumes.
音量
And those are centered around the portal.
而这些都是围绕入口的中心
So I've got my blue portal here and that was green volumes here.
所以我在这里有一个蓝色的入口 这是绿色的卷
And you'll notice it's entirely in front of the portal--
你会注意到它完全在入口的前面--
that's important.
这一点很重要
And then we've got this yellow volume here.
然后我们就有了这本黄色的书
So the yellow volume is--
所以黄色的体积是--
it's whole job is to tell us which objects in the world
它的全部工作就是告诉我们世界上哪些物体
are just kind of close to a portal, and I'll come back
就在传送门附近 我会回来的
to why that's important to the minute.
为什么这是最重要的一分钟
But it separates us from having to think about objects
但它使我们不必去思考物体
that are way out in the world all over in the white space around here.
它们在世界各地的白色空间里是遥不可及的
We don't have to think about them.
我们不需要考虑他们
And we also know they're not objects behind the portal
我们也知道它们不是门户后面的物体
because we're only interested in stuff that happens in front of the portal.
因为我们只对门户前发生的事情感兴趣
And this green volume here is where most of the magic happens.
而这里的绿色空间是大部分魔力发生的地方
This volume says the objects in it are so close to a portal
这本书说里面的物体离入口太近了
we need to think very hard about what they can do and what they can't do.
我们需要非常认真地思考他们能做什么 不能做什么
We're going to let those objects start passing through the portal.
我们要让这些物体开始通过传送门
And so we keep these objects in two separate lists.
因此 我们将这些对象放在两个单独的列表中
Objects that are in this green volume no longer intersect with any objects
此绿色体积中的对象不再与任何对象相交
out in the white space out here.
在外面的白色空间里
They don't have to think about them.
他们不需要考虑这些问题
They're kept in a completely separate list
它们被保存在一个完全不同的列表中
and they don't collide with them at all.
它们根本不会与它们相撞
They also don't collide with world geometry.
它们也不会与世界几何体发生碰撞
I'll get to that in a bit.
我稍后会讲到这一点
And then objects in this yellow volume are
然后这个黄色体积中的物体是
the only ones that the objects in the green volume have to worry about.
绿色体积中的物体唯一需要担心的是
So these are objects that are just kind of close to a portal.
所以这些物体就像是靠近入口的东西
And so another important interaction with portals is ray casting.
因此 与门户的另一个重要交互是光线投射
So we're only interested in rays that pass through the portal quad.
所以我们只对穿过传送门四边形的射线感兴趣
So if a ray happens to just pass the portal plane,
因此 如果光线恰好通过入射平面
but not intersect the quad, we don't do anything with it.
但不是与四边形相交 我们不会对它做任何事情
It's not special.
这没什么特别的
We just treat it like any other ray in the world
我们只是像对待世界上任何其他射线一样对待它
and let it do its merry thing.
让它去做它快乐的事情
But we got this magenta guy.
但我们找到了这个洋红色的家伙
It intersects with the portal.
它与入口相交
So now we have to recast a new ray out the other orange portal which
所以现在我们必须重新投射出另一个橙色入口的新射线
essentially gives us two ray segments.
基本上给了我们两个光线段
And if you think about that, if you were to write any piece of code that
如果你想一下 如果你要写任何一段代码
just did the ray casting and hand back two ray segments
刚刚进行了光线投射并交还了两个光线片段
when somebody was expecting one, you're probably going to get weird results.
当有人在期待的时候 你可能会得到奇怪的结果
So this means, the fact that this is happening,
所以这意味着 事实是 这种情况正在发生
means that we have to go through every single system in the game that possibly
这意味着我们必须通过游戏中的每一个系统
casts a ray through a portal and fix every single one to understand.
通过传送门投射一条射线 并修复每一个以理解
But if we give you back multiple segments, different things happen.
但如果我们给你多个片段 就会发生不同的事情
Instead of assuming that this starting point goes directly
与其假设这个起点直接
to this end point, which doesn't even go in the direction
到这个终点 它甚至不是朝向
it wanted to in the first place.
它一开始就想这么做
And so at its core, remember how I told you
所以在它的核心 记得我是怎么告诉你的
every object had an origin, a single point that
每个物体都有一个原点 一个点
defines where it is in space.
定义它在空间中的位置
We use the ray casting to determine if an object that's
我们使用光线投射来确定一个对象是否
in this green volume and just kind of moving around.
在这个绿色的体积里 就像是在四处走动
We use a recast from one point where it was
我们用重铸的方式从一个点开始重铸
one frame to one point where it was another frame
从一帧到另一帧的一点
to see if it either passed through a portal or outside the portal
以查看它是通过门户还是在门户之外
because if it went over this way, we do nothing at all.
因为如果事情朝这个方向发展 我们什么都不会做
If we went this way, we need to teleport it.
如果我们走这条路 我们需要传送它
So that's the basics of our handling.
这就是我们处理的基本方法
So how do we let objects pass through walls?
那么我们如何让物体穿过墙壁呢？
This is one of the things I spent a whole lot of time
这是我花了很多时间
on because we wanted our portal transitions to be very seamless.
因为我们希望我们的门户过渡非常无缝
Remember in one of my first slides I showed you.
还记得我给你们看的第一张幻灯片吗
It should be like a door.
它应该像一扇门
People expect to walk halfway through the door and just stand there.
人们希望走到门的一半 只是站在那里
And how we do this is--
我们要做的是
I'm going to talk about it a bit first.
我先讲一下
Whenever you place a portal, we take a snapshot of all the world geometry
无论何时你放置一个传送门 我们都会对所有的世界几何形状进行快照
around you and create a very small representation of that
在你周围创造一个非常小的代表
and carve a hole in it.
然后在上面刻个洞
And we don't do this for the entire world because that takes way too long.
我们不为全世界做这件事 因为这需要太长的时间
And by way too long, I mean a quarter of a second.
太长了 我是说四分之一秒
And in game terms, that's just way too long.
从游戏的角度来说 这太长了
I don't know if it was a quarter of a second.
我不知道是不是四分之一秒
I remember originally that we had a problem where
我记得最初我们有一个问题
I think carving the mini-version took a quarter of a second,
我想雕刻迷你版花了四分之一秒
so it probably took several seconds.
所以可能花了几秒钟
So I'm going to show you a scenario here where I've got a portal
我将给你们展示一个场景 我有一个入口
and it's going into--
它将进入--
it's going along this corridor gateway, gangplank thing.
它沿着这个走廊入口走 跳板什么的
And it's going to go into this little classroom area.
它将进入这个小教室区域
And as I go back around the wall, I'm going
当我绕着墙走的时候
to show you a debug mesh of our collision representation.
给你们看一个我们的碰撞表示的调试网格
So in this debug representation, we've got these green lines.
在这个调试表示中 我们有这些绿线
These green lines and then also these cyan lines--
这些绿线和这些蓝线
or I'm probably mispronouncing that.
或者我可能读错了
I call them bluish, but my colleague has told me I need to call him cyan.
我叫它们蓝色 但我的同事告诉我 我需要叫他青色
[CHUCKLING]
[吃吃地笑]
So I'm going to call them bluish now.
所以我现在把它们叫做蓝色
So these green lines and the blue lines are in local space.
这些绿线和蓝线是局部空间
So they're with the blue portal that we placed locally.
所以他们和我们在本地放置的蓝色入口在一起
And I know it's super hard to see, but there
我知道这很难看出来 但是
are a bunch of red lines over here and some magenta ones.
这里有一堆红线和一些洋红色的
Those are from the other portal that's in the classroom that
这些来自教室里的另一个入口
are flipped and glued to the back of our local portal.
被翻转并粘在我们当地门户的后面
So it's all in this local space and around this blue portal.
所以它都在这个本地空间和这个蓝色门户周围
We put some new stuff behind it and some new stuff in front of it.
我们在它后面放了一些新东西 在它前面放了一些新东西
And so you may be asking yourself what the colors actually mean?
因此 你可能会问自己 这些颜色到底意味着什么？
Green here is representing a brush geometry, which most level editors, you
这里的绿色代表画笔几何体 大多数关卡编辑器 你可以
can create walls and various shapes directly in the level editor.
可以直接在关卡编辑器中创建墙和各种形状
And at least in our terminology, we refer to these as brushes.
至少在我们的术语中 我们将这些称为刷子
So they're usually very simple convex shapes and super easy to deal with.
所以它们通常是非常简单的凸起形状 非常容易处理
And this bluish geometry is from what's known
这个蓝色的几何图形来自已知的
as a static prop, which is a model that somebody modeled in a model editor.
作为静态道具 这是某人在模型编辑器中建模的模型
So it's going to be arbitrarily complex, but it
所以这将是任意复杂的 但它
has to be made up of convex shapes.
必须由凸起的形状组成
But we take a small snapshot of that and then carve it up.
但我们会拍一张小快照 然后把它分割开来
Sorry, I forgot to mention.
对不起 我忘了提了
So we call it a static prop because we are guaranteed it does not move.
所以我们称它为静态道具 因为我们保证它不会移动
And that's very important because it's really easy to simulate things that
这一点非常重要 因为它很容易模拟出
don't move.
不许动
They don't move.
他们一动不动
And the same is true of the red and magenta here.
这里的红色和洋红色也是如此
The red is the brush geometry on the paired portal side
红色是成对门户侧的笔刷几何图形
and the magenta is static props on the other side, which is mainly the desks.
而洋红色是另一边的静态道具 主要是桌子
And as I'm looking through here.
当我从这里看过去的时候
You can see just a small snapshot, and then you
你可以看到一个小的快照 然后你
can see this magenta outline here of the desk mesh on the other side.
可以在这里看到这个洋红色的轮廓 在另一边的书桌网状物
It's important to know that that's not me looking at the mesh
重要的是要知道 看网眼的不是我
through the portal.
通过传送门
That's the local space version and it just
这是当地的太空版 它只是
happens to line up the desk because we have to make sure everything lines up.
碰巧把桌子排成一排 因为我们必须确保一切都排好
Otherwise your physical interactions will seem weird
否则你们的身体互动会看起来很奇怪
if something is halfway in a portal and it's
如果某个东西在传送门的一半 它是
kind of not colliding with something or it's colliding with it wrong.
好像没有撞到什么东西 或者撞错了
As I walk through, you'll notice all the colors
当我走过时 你会注意到所有的颜色
change because we switched spaces when I walk through in a second.
改变 因为我们交换了空间 当我走过一秒钟
So now all the colors are local space for this side.
所以现在所有的颜色都是这一边的局部空间
So, yeah, that is how we carve a hole.
所以 是的 这就是我们挖洞的方式
It's a very, very small area of the level that we carve a hole in.
这是一个非常非常小的区域 我们可以在上面挖一个洞
And so we're getting back to the volumes I showed you two slides ago.
所以我们回到我在两张幻灯片前展示过的内容
If we carve a small representation of the world,
如果我们雕刻一小块世界的图画
we have to know when the player is colliding
我们必须知道球员何时发生碰撞
with that versus the regular world.
在这一点上与常规世界相比
Because if they're colliding with the regular world,
因为如果它们与常规世界发生碰撞
they're going to collide with the wall that's behind the portal
他们会撞上传送门后面的墙
and they're not going to go through it.
他们不会经历这一切的
So we have to use exclusively that carved version
所以我们必须独家使用那个雕刻版本
when they're close to a portal.
当他们靠近传送门的时候
And we do that-- we're using the same volumes I was talking about earlier.
我们这样做--我们使用的是我之前说过的相同的体积
This is a 3D representation of them.
这是它们的3D表示
And you'll notice that they have space--
你会注意到它们有空间--
a large amount of space above and below the portal.
入口上方和下方的大量空间
That's important because it's a 3D space instead of a 2D space.
这一点很重要 因为它是3D空间 而不是2D空间
So as I enter the yellow space, I still collide with the world.
因此 当我进入黄色空间时 我仍然与世界相撞
I still collide with all the desks and things.
我仍然会撞上所有的桌子和东西
Because I'm still-- while I'm exclusively in the yellow volume,
因为我还在--虽然我只在黄色卷里
I'm still colliding with the world.
我还在与这个世界碰撞
I'm going to show you.
我要给你们展示一下
It's a bad example, but it's the video I've got.
这是一个不好的例子 但这是我得到的视频
I'm going to hit this chair behind this desk
我要撞到这张桌子后面的椅子
because it's still in the real world.
因为它还在真实的世界里
And then as I transition into the green volume,
然后当我过渡到绿色音量时
I am exclusively colliding with our carved version of it.
我完全是在与我们雕刻的版本发生碰撞
Which-- that was a bad frame to cut.
这--这是一个糟糕的框架削减
If I happen to look back in the portal--
如果我碰巧回过头来看传送门--
which side is scrubbing?
哪一方在擦洗？
OK.
好的
Sorry.
抱歉的
So if you happen to look inside the portal, you might be able to see it.
因此 如果你碰巧在入口内看 你可能会看到它
There is-- I know it's super hard to see, I'm sorry.
有--我知道这很难看 对不起
But we did carve a hole.
但我们确实挖了一个洞
There's no there's no geometry right here to stop us going in.
不 这里没有几何学阻止我们进入
And since we're exclusively using this new mesh,
由于我们只使用这种新的网状物
we're allowed to just go through that space.
我们被允许只通过那个空间
OK, so more importantly than static geometry, which
好的 所以比静态几何更重要的是
doesn't move and is super easy to physically simulate,
不会移动 而且非常容易物理模拟
we have dynamic props and things that move.
我们有充满活力的道具和可以移动的东西
Specifically in this case, boxes.
特别是在这种情况下 盒子
So the way we model this is very similar to how we did with geometry.
因此 我们建模的方式与我们处理几何体的方式非常相似
We're going to be duplicating everything and I'm
我们要复制所有的东西 而我
going to show you by walking in a portal.
我将通过走进传送门来向你展示
So this blue box that just appeared is my player.
所以刚才出现的这个蓝色盒子就是我的播放器
My player of physics object that's replicated from this orange portal
我的物理玩家从这个橙色的门户复制的对象
to the backside of the blue portal.
蓝色传送门的背面
And this is using a system known as a physics shadow.
这是使用一种被称为物理阴影的系统
At least that's what our system is.
至少我们的系统是这样的
I'm not really a physicist.
我不是一个真正的物理学家
That's just what we call our representation of it.
这就是我们所说的我们对它的表现
So I mean, I haven't dealt with many physics systems when I talk about that.
所以我的意思是 当我谈到这一点时 我还没有处理过太多的物理系统
So what a physics shadow does that's different
所以物理阴影的作用是不同的
than our rendering geometry is we're not allowed to actually teleport it
比我们的渲染几何体更重要的是 我们不能真正地传送它
from one frame to the next because if you teleport a physics
从一帧到下一帧 因为如果你传送一个物理
object, then all sorts of interactions that intersect,
对象 然后各种相交的交互作用
they have no previous basis to go from.
他们没有以前的基础可言
Of like how to solve that.
比如如何解决这个问题
They can't rewind time because they've suddenly teleported
他们不能让时间倒流 因为他们突然传送了
into an interpenetrating space.
进入一个相互穿透的空间
So all of our physics objects--
所以我们所有的物理物体--
we give them a target of where they need to go.
我们给他们一个目标 告诉他们需要去哪里
Sorry not all of our physics options are shadows.
抱歉 并不是所有的物理选项都是阴影
So just like the player volume and just the examples I'm about to give you.
所以就像播放器音量和我接下来给你们的例子一样
We told them where we want them to go and they try their best
我们告诉他们我们想要他们去的地方 他们尽了最大努力
to apply forces and rotations to go there, but if it doesn't work,
向那里施加力和旋转 但如果它不起作用
we're kind of SOL and they do their best.
我们有点像索尔 他们会尽力的
So I'm replicating that for the player over there.
所以我正在为那边的玩家复制这一点
And we're also going to replicate it for the cubes in a second
我们还将在一秒钟内为立方体复制它
once I get around to placing them.
一旦我抽出时间来摆放它们
And so it's important to note that we're not really
所以重要的是要注意 我们并不是真的
solving the discontinuity in space because that
解决空间中的不连续性 因为
would be way too hard, at least for a person of my skill level.
这太难了 至少对我这种技术水平的人来说
What we're doing is we're saying each side has--
我们所做的是 我们说双方都有--
this cube over here is the master of it's physics and this cube over here
这个立方体是它的物理学大师
is the master of its own physics.
是自身物理学的大师
And this cube over here is just trying to replicate
这个立方体只是想复制
whatever this guy is doing.
不管这家伙在做什么
So they don't quite line up, but they work well enough.
所以它们并不完全一致 但它们工作得很好
And in game development, good enough usually goes a long way.
在游戏开发中 足够好通常会走很长的路
So as I'm using it, you might notice they don't quite work super well,
所以当我使用它的时候 你可能会注意到它们并不是很好用
but you can see that I've got this representation over here.
但你可以看到我在这里有一个代表
I'm pushing it in my virtual version and it's all lining up kind of.
我在我的虚拟版本中推动它 所有的东西都在排队
And, yeah, that's how we do it in Portal.
是的 这就是我们在《传送门》中的做法
So I'm going to go ahead and tell you that I'm really glad that we
所以我要告诉你们我很高兴我们
didn't have levels with more than two cubes because if you try to do this
我没有超过两个立方体的关卡 因为如果你试着这样做
with a train of cubes-- three or four--
有一列立方体--三四个--
it breaks down horribly.
它会坏得很厉害
And this last little bit is me just showing you
最后一点是我向你们展示的
that we're not intersecting with anything in the back of it
我们没有和它后面的任何东西相交
because we're not inside the green volume or the yellow volume
因为我们不在绿色或黄色的区域内
because we're behind the portal.
因为我们在传送门后面
It's really important to manage your lists of what can interact with what
管理你的列表是非常重要的
when we're faking holes in space and overlapping space.
当我们在空间中伪造洞和重叠空间时
I spent a whole lot of time on this.
我在这上面花了很多时间
And I think that is the end of our physics material.
我想我们的物理材料就到此为止了
So we had some more miscellaneous filler material,
所以我们有了更多的杂项填充材料
but it looks like we've ran over a little bit of our initial time.
但看起来我们已经超过了最初的时间
So we're going to open up to Q&amp;A now.
所以我们现在要开始问答了
We might get to our miscellaneous material later.
我们以后可能会谈到我们的杂项材料
But, yeah, if anybody has got questions, now would be a good time.
但是 如果有人有问题 现在是个好时机
AUDIENCE: Could you talk a little bit about how lights interact with portals,
观众：你能谈谈灯光是如何与门户互动的吗？
or just lighting on objects and, like, will you get shadows from the portal?
或者只是在物体上照明 比如 你会从入口得到阴影吗？
DAVE KIRCHER: So originally, I had a slide on that.
戴夫·奇彻：最初 我有一张幻灯片
TEJEEV KOHLI: The question was about lights.
TEJEEV KOHLI：这个问题是关于灯的
DAVE KIRCHER: Oh, sorry.
戴夫·基尔希：哦 对不起
Yes, sorry.
是的 对不起
The question was how lights interact with portals and shadows and things.
问题是光是如何与入口、阴影和其他东西相互作用的
So I'm going to preface with saying that most of this stuff I did a decade ago.
所以我想先说的是 我十年前做的大部分事情
So if I say something that's not true, I'm not trying to lie.
所以如果我说了假话 我不是在撒谎
I just don't remember it.
我就是不记得了
So basically there was a time during Portal 1
所以基本上在传送门1的时候
where we tried very hard to make light work through portals
在那里我们非常努力地让光通过传送门
and we kind of settled on a cheap solution.
我们决定用一种便宜的方法
Where we would define a point barely in front of one portal,
我们会在一个入口前定义一个点
see what lights were projecting what amount of color on that,
看看是什么光投射了多少颜色
and just kind of make it a massive sphere on the other side that
在另一边做成一个巨大的球体
would kind of do that.
会这么做
So the downside was is that you only noticed it
所以缺点就是你只注意到了
in cases that were very high contrast, which is also the case in where
在对比度非常高的情况下
it was the most broken.
是最破的
So we just don't do it.
所以我们不做
TEJEEV KOHLI: On Portal 2, we tried for a while
TEJEEV KOHLI：在传送门2上 我们尝试了一段时间
to have the portals themselves project light on things
让传送门本身将光线投射到物体上
and that was also kind of broken for a while.
也有一段时间被打破了
And then we just took it out.
然后我们就把它取出来了
DAVE KIRCHER: Yes, so we just punted on that one.
戴夫·基尔彻：是的 所以我们只是在这一点上下注
Too hard.
不难.
TEJEEV KOHLI: Any other questions?
TEJEEV KOHLI：还有其他问题吗？
Yeah, sure.
好的当然
AUDIENCE: What were the performance implications
观众：对性能的影响是什么
of having to draw on that stencil buffer multiple times?
需要在模板缓冲区中多次绘制吗
DAVE KIRCHER: So the question was what were the performance
戴夫·基尔彻：所以问题是
implications of having to draw multiple scenes with the stencil buffer.
这意味着必须使用模具缓冲区绘制多个场景
So it's very analogous having to just draw a more complex scene.
所以这和画一个更复杂的场景很相似
You're just drawing more quads and things.
你只是在画更多的四边形什么的
On one of the slides in our miscellaneous section--
在我们杂项部分的一张幻灯片上--
you know what?
你知道吗？
Why don't I just go ahead and jump to it?
我为什么不直接说呢？
So it's very important.
所以这很重要
So when we're rendering things in a 3D space,
所以当我们在3D空间中渲染事物时
we have what's known as a frustum.
我们有一个所谓的平截头体
It's kind of a pyramid, which comes out from your camera.
有点像金字塔 从你的相机里出来
And you can use it as a very quick test to see if you should even
你可以用它作为一个非常快速的测试 看看你是否应该
bother rendering something at all.
也懒得去渲染什么
So I've got--
所以我有
I'm going to use my side--
我要用我这边
my sides.
我的两侧
The sides are defined by the screen itself.
这些边是由屏幕本身定义的
So the screen that you're drawing has a top, has a bottom,
所以你画的屏幕有一个顶部 有一个底部
so those project into space.
所以这些东西投射到太空中
So we take our one side we can say, OK, if an object is completely
所以我们站在一边 我们可以说 如果一个物体完全
on the other side of this plane, we don't even
在飞机的另一边 我们甚至不
need to bother trying to draw it.
我需要费心去画它
We can just skip it.
我们可以跳过它
And so one of the optimizations we have in Portal
因此 我们在门户网站中进行的优化之一
is that every time you look through a portal,
就是每次你通过传送门看的时候
we can find the frustum to a smaller space.
我们可以找到一个更小的空间的平台体
I took the easy route in that I kept it as an object that
我选择了一条简单的路线 因为我把它作为一个物体保存下来
still had four distinct sides.
仍然有四个截然不同的方面
So sometimes it's a little bit broken.
所以有时候它有点坏了
But in this case, you can see--
但在这种情况下 你可以看到--
in this case, you can see I'm looking through a blue portal
在这种情况下 您可以看到我正在通过一个蓝色的入口查看
at this little button here.
在这里的这个小按钮上
And I've got this-- it's probably impossible to see,
我得到了这个--它可能是不可能看到的
but I've got this mesh coming out.
但我已经把这个网状物拿出来了
This is the updated frustum of everything we try to draw.
这是我们试图绘制的所有东西的最新平截体
So you can see it mostly just encapsulates a little bit of level
所以你可以看到 它主要是封装了一些级别
and the button itself, and that helps us not even attempt to draw
以及按钮本身 这有助于我们甚至不尝试绘制
the complete scene over and over again.
一遍又一遍的完整场景
But I don't think I ever did a performance analysis,
但我想我从来没有做过性能分析
so I can't give you concrete numbers.
所以我不能给你具体的数字
But it was better than trying to draw the entire scene over and over again.
但这比试图一遍又一遍地画整个场景要好
Because since we still had the depth buffer on our side,
因为既然我们这边还有深度缓冲
we had already drawn most of the screen.
我们已经画出了屏幕的大部分
And then we also had the stencil buffer telling us
然后我们也有模板缓冲区告诉我们
not to even attempt to draw most of the pixels.
甚至不会尝试绘制大部分像素
It was not nearly as bad as trying to render the entire scene.
这远没有试图渲染整个场景那么糟糕
But we did find that for the graphics cards of the day, which not even
但我们确实发现了当时的显卡 这甚至不是
all of them supported stencil buffers.
它们都支持模板缓冲区
Some people that played Portal 1, they got textures.
一些玩传送门1的人 他们得到了纹理
We found it was best to just limit to two recursions
我们发现最好将递归限制为两次
because we could do our depth, or we could do our recursion fake
因为我们可以做我们的深度 或者我们可以做我们的递归假
and it worked pretty well.
而且它运行得很好
And I don't think it was terribly expensive
我不认为它是非常昂贵的
even for the cards of the day.
即使是在今天的纸牌上
TEJEEV KOHLI: I know there were cases during Portal 2
TEJEEV Kohli：我知道在2号传送门期间有一些病例
when we were trying to make it work on consoles,
当我们试图让它在游戏机上工作时
there was a lot of proof tests.
有很多的验证测试
There were four cases, especially in co-op,
有四个案例 特别是在合作社
when you're playing in split-screen with four portals on screen at the same time
当您在屏幕上同时显示四个入口的分屏模式下玩游戏时
all looking at each other.
大家都面面相觑
It's like 16 views being rendered of the entire world at the same time.
这就像是同时渲染了整个世界的16个视图
And there were these like weird edge cases where like,
有一些奇怪的边缘案例 比如
if you do that, you get two frames per second.
如果你这样做 你会得到每秒两帧
Just don't do that.
不要那样做
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
There was a few things in levels that had changed where--
有一些东西在水平上发生了变化--
like the corner case was the worst.
好像角落里的案子是最糟糕的
Where if you have a wall like that and you
如果你有这样一堵墙 而你
can put a portal right next to each other on both sides of the corner.
可以在角落的两侧放置一个紧挨着的入口
So we had a couple of cases where we had to actually change the levels
所以我们有几个案例 我们不得不实际改变水平
to not have those cases.
不再有那些案子
So you can't play--
所以你不能玩--
so we just moved the corners apart like 16 units or whatever.
所以我们只是把角落分开了 大概有16个单元之类的
So you can't always see both portals through both the views.
因此 您不能总是通过两个视图同时看到两个门户
So there was stuff like that we had to work through especially
所以有一些类似的事情我们必须特别地解决
for consoles back in the day.
在以前的游戏机上
Like we were working on PS3 360s.
就像我们在PS3 360上工作一样
I'm sure now it's better, but it's been a long time since we've done that.
我相信现在好多了 但我们已经很久没这么做了
DAVE KIRCHER: If I remember correctly, using stenciling
戴夫·科尔彻：如果我没记错的话 使用的是模版印刷
was strictly less expensive than using textures,
比使用纹理要便宜得多
because you're still going to draw the same amount of geometry,
因为你仍然要画相同数量的几何体
but you have no texture cost whatsoever.
但你没有任何质地成本
Hopefully that answers most of that.
希望这能回答大部分问题
AUDIENCE: How did you cover all of your bases for each level,
观众：你是如何覆盖每一关的所有基础的
so that a player could never get stuck?
这样球员就永远不会被卡住了？
In the sense that if you fell off a cliff
从这个意义上说 如果你从悬崖上掉下来
or maybe accidentally erased a portal, you could always find a way to go back
或者是不小心抹去了一个传送门 你总能找到回到过去的方法
or to keep progressing forward?
还是继续前进？
TEJEEV KOHLI: The question was about how we
TEJEEV Kohli：问题是我们如何
covered our bases to make sure the players can't get stuck in levels
覆盖了我们的基地 以确保球员不会陷入关卡
if they do something bad.
如果他们做了坏事
Mostly through play testing and then later on through bug testing.
主要是通过播放测试 然后是错误测试
It's a lot of just trying to make sure that you can see parts of the level
这是一项很大的工作 只是为了确保你能看到水平的一部分
from different parts.
来自不同的地方
Towards the later process of when we're getting closer to shipping,
到后来的过程 当我们越来越接近发货时
we do something called the greasy pig pass for the levels.
我们做一种叫做油腻的猪通行证的水平
Where we make sure the players can't literally get stuck on walls and stuff
在那里我们确保玩家不会真的被困在墙上
as they're walking through them.
当他们穿过它们的时候
So we have a bunch of invisible geometry there
所以我们有一堆看不见的几何图形
that'll make smooth the collisions along stairs and along--
这将使沿楼梯和沿-的碰撞变得平滑
because especially in Portal 2, there's a bunch of these broken pieces
因为特别是在2号传送门 有一堆这样的碎片
and a bunch of foliage and broken parts of the levels
还有一堆树叶和水平的破碎部分
that are tilted at weird angles and stuff.
以奇怪的角度倾斜之类的东西
And it's like for the most part, we left them as is.
在很大程度上 我们让它们保持原样
But a lot of cases we had to go in and put invisible stuff
但很多情况下 我们不得不把无形的东西放进去
everywhere to make sure that the wall might
以确保这堵墙可能
look like it's broken up into like 15 different pieces,
看起来像是被分成了15个不同的部分
but the player's just colliding with a flat plane.
但玩家只是撞上了一架平板飞机
It's to make sure that those things don't happen where
它是为了确保这些事情不会发生在
the players don't get stuck in spots.
球员们不会卡在斑点上
And there's also a bunch of level design work that goes around and making sure--
也有一系列的水平设计工作 确保--
because we have to take care of the opposite as well, right?
因为我们也要照顾到相反的情况 对吗？
We have to take care of, well, we've got to make
我们得照顾好 嗯 我们得
sure the player can see the exit portal from the start of the level
当然 玩家可以从关卡的起点看到出口入口
so they can't just portal and portal and get to the end.
因此 他们不能只通过门户和门户就能走到最后
And so doing that process helps with what you are asking as well.
因此 这样做也有助于你所提出的问题
Because if you can make sure that the exploits aren't there,
因为如果你能确保漏洞不在那里
you're also getting rid of cases where the player can get themselves
你也摆脱了玩家可以让自己
in a bad spot.
在一个糟糕的位置
And so it kind of works itself out through the course of development.
因此 它在某种程度上是通过发展过程自行解决的
You don't go in starting to make a puzzle
你不会一开始就做一个拼图
or making a level with that in mind a whole lot.
或者在脑海中充分利用这一点
But as you start refining it, things get tweaked and things get tuned.
但当你开始改进它时 事情就会调整 事情就会调整
Some things you might be have to tweak for like port reasons.
由于端口等原因 您可能需要对某些内容进行调整
Like this doesn't work on PS3.
这在PS3上是行不通的
So you got to go, OK, I got to fix this and tweak the puzzle a little bit.
所以你得走了 好的 我得解决这个问题 稍微调整一下拼图
But then once you tweak the puzzle, now you've
但一旦你调整了拼图 现在你就
got to do the whole testing all over again.
整个测试得从头再来一遍
Because all right, I can't just put a portal place on there
因为好吧 我不能就这么把门楼放在那里
because now you can solve the puzzle without doing any of it.
因为现在你不需要做任何事情就可以解开谜题
So there's a bunch of work that has to go on from that sense.
因此 从这个意义上说 还有很多工作要做
DAVE KIRCHER: And it's important to note that as we
戴夫·科尔彻：需要注意的是 当我们
get closer to shipping a product, more and more of our dev team
更接近于发货产品 我们的开发团队中越来越多的人
switches to play testing.
切换到播放测试
And we have some very smart and mischievous people
我们有一些非常聪明和淘气的人
that that specific question of how do you make sure you don't get stuck
具体的问题是 你如何确保你不会被困在
is on the checklist.
都在核对表上
It was on my checklist at least of, like, I am
它至少在我的清单上 就像 我是
going to make sure I can't get stuck.
以确保我不会被卡住
I'm going to sit in this level for about half an hour
我要在这个楼层坐大约半个小时
and think long and hard about how to get myself stuck.
好好想一想如何让自己陷入困境
And if I can't do it, then pass.
如果我做不到 那就算了
[CHUCKLES]
[咯咯地笑]
AUDIENCE: Was there anything that you would have liked to have pursued,
观众：你有没有想要追求的东西
but didn't, due to either time constraints on shipping
但没有 因为运输的时间限制
or the limitations of graphics cards of the day that you thought about,
或者你当时想到的显卡的局限性
but for whatever reason, couldn't do?
但不管是什么原因 都做不到？
DAVE KIRCHER: The question was was there anything
戴夫·科尔彻：问题是有没有
that we didn't pursue for various reasons before shipping?
我们在发货前出于各种原因没有追查的产品吗？
And I can't think of anything.
我什么都想不起来
I think I was pretty happy with what we produced.
我想我对我们制作的东西很满意
Most of the things I focused on were bugs
我关注的大部分东西都是错误
that we shipped because once again, getting back into shipping mode,
我们发货是因为再一次回到发货模式
as you get closer to shipping something, you
当你离发货越来越近时 你
want to touch the code less and less and less.
想要接触的代码越来越少
Even if you know that the fix is going to work 100%, it will definitely work,
即使你知道修复将100%奏效 它也肯定会奏效
it might break something new.
它可能会打破一些新的东西
So I certainly have a small list of things that I wished I had fixed,
所以我当然有一个小小的清单 上面列出了我希望自己能解决的事情
but nothing that I wish I--
但我并不希望...
AUDIENCE: Basically, like, features like the sticky paint, for example.
观众：基本上 比如说 像粘性油漆这样的功能
DAVE KIRCHER: Yeah, yeah.
戴夫·科尔彻：是的 是的
Yeah, I can't think of any features that--
我想不出有什么特征
TEJEEV KOHLI: There's stuff that we worked on that
TEJEEV KOHLI：我们做了一些工作
obviously didn't ed up shipping.
很明显没有增加运输量
Some of them we touched on over here.
其中一些我们在这里提到过
I don't know if sticky paint was something
我不知道是不是因为
that we should have worked more on, though,
我们应该多花点心思
because I feel like we spent a lot of time trying to get it to work.
因为我觉得我们花了很长时间才让它发挥作用
And the reasons for cutting it then are still valid now.
当时削减它的理由现在仍然有效
So I'm saying if we were to go back, I don't think
所以我是说如果我们回去 我不认为
we would try to solve that problem.
我们会努力解决这个问题
We'd probably come up with new problems to try to solve.
我们可能会想出新的问题来解决
We did have-- like another thing we tried
我们试过另一种方法
was I think we tried it after the game shipped for like a DLC expansion was
我认为我们在游戏发布后尝试了它 就像DLC扩展一样
reflection paint.
反光漆
So it was paint that would reflect the different elements of the games
因此 这是油漆 将反映不同的元素的游戏
like reflect lasers or reflect light bridges.
比如反射激光或者反射光桥
And we didn't get too far with it.
但我们没能走得太远
Again, it leads to a bunch of weird levels
同样 它导致了一堆奇怪的水平
because you have to have all levels have angles.
因为你必须让每一层都有角度
Because if you think about Portal, most of the levels
因为如果你想想传送门
are like 90 degree walls and stuff.
像是90度的墙什么的
And 90 degree reflections don't go anywhere.
90度的反射无处不在
So we had to have--
所以我们不得不
make this super contrived looking levels with these weird 45 degree angles
用这些奇怪的45度角制作这个超级人为的外观水平
everywhere and they can reflect things.
到处都是 它们可以反映事物
And then all the problems like, well, how often--
然后所有的问题 好吧 多久一次
how many bounces do we allow and things.
我们允许多少次反弹之类的
And also stuff just looked weird, like tractor beams reflecting off
还有一些东西看起来很奇怪 像拖拉机光束反射到
of walls just looked weird.
看起来很奇怪
There's probably other ideas that I can't remember right now,
可能还有其他的想法我现在记不起来了
but there are--
但也有
a lot of them get cut short pretty quick because the flaws are really apparent
他们中的很多人很快就被砍掉了 因为缺陷非常明显
pretty quickly.
很快
You might sit down and think, oh, this is a great idea.
你可能会坐下来想 哦 这是个好主意
I'm going to go out and work on it.
我要出去工作了
And then as you start working through it and testing it out with others,
然后当你开始通过它并与其他人一起测试它时
you start seeing all the problems.
你开始看到所有的问题
And those problems get apparent pretty quickly.
这些问题很快就会显现出来
And at that point, you make the call.
到了那个时候 你就可以打电话了
Just be like, this is not worth pursuing anymore.
就像 这不值得再追求了
We had some more game modes we were trying to work on.
我们有更多的游戏模式 我们正在努力工作
I think we had a competitive mode for a little bit we worked on.
我认为我们有一个竞争模式 我们工作了一点
DAVE KIRCHER: We actually have a slide about that for a little bit.
戴夫·奇彻：我们实际上有一个关于这个的幻灯片
It didn't get fleshed out.
它没有得到充实
But after Portal shipped, we immediately said
但传送门出货后我们马上说
to ourself what does multiplayer look like?
多人游戏是什么样子的？
And so the first thing we tried was deathmatch.
所以我们首先尝试的是死亡竞赛
Turns out that's a horrible idea.
事实证明这是一个可怕的想法
Everybody wants to just put portals under other people's feet.
每个人都想把传送门放在别人的脚下
So you spend most of your time just completely disoriented or confused.
所以你大部分时间都是晕头转向
And then I think we made a collect the coins kind of like,
然后我想我们做了一个收集硬币有点像
oh, do flings and things.
哦 做一些狂欢之类的事情
But once again, everybody wanted to put their portals
但再一次 每个人都想把他们的门户网站
under other people's feet.
踩在别人的脚下
So now we have co-op.
所以现在我们有了合作
TEJEEV KOHLI: The co-op was very successful, I think.
TEJEEV KOHLI：我认为合作社非常成功
And there's a bunch of other challenges that come
还有很多其他的挑战
with co-op that we had to work through.
我们必须解决的问题
I think, yeah, we tried some more different competitive modes.
我认为 是的 我们尝试了一些不同的竞争模式
We tried a time trial kind of mode, but they're doing it together.
我们尝试了计时赛的模式 但他们是一起做的
But that's effectively just playing two single player games at the same time.
但这实际上只是同时玩两个单人游戏
So there's not much interaction.
所以没有太多的互动
Any time you let players interact in a competitive way in Portal,
任何时候你让玩家在《传送门》中以竞争的方式互动
they just want to put portals on their feet.
他们只想把传送门装在脚上
That's really all they want to do.
这就是他们真正想做的
It's fun for a bit, but not as the receiving end, right?
这是有趣的一点 但不是作为接收端 对不对？
It's not fun-- or they just want to keep bumping each other's portals.
这并不有趣--或者他们只是想继续撞对方的门户
Like when they want to put their portal at exactly where the other guy's
就像他们想把传送门放在另一个人
portal is.
波特尔群岛
Like they walk in and they go in there instead
就像他们走进来然后进去
of where they were supposed to go.
他们应该去的地方
It's fun for a bit.
暂时还挺有趣的
I'm not saying there's no merit there.
我不是说这没有价值
DAVE KIRCHER: By "a bit," I think he means about five minutes.
戴夫·基尔彻：我想他说的“一点”是指大约五分钟
TEJEEV KOHLI: Yeah, by "a bit," that's the thing you look at, you're like, ah,
TEJEEV KOHLI：是的 通过“一点” 这就是你看到的东西 你就像 啊
that's funny.
真好笑
But then you realize there's no real--
但后来你意识到没有真正的.
at least in the mechanics we tried, there wasn't much depth to it.
至少在我们尝试的机制中 它没有太多的深度
It's not something you could flesh out for a game mode.
这不是你可以在游戏模式中充实的东西
It's more of something you could do as a level--
这更多的是你可以作为一个层次来做的事情--
as a gimmick once.
曾经是个噱头
But then there's not much reason to do that.
但也没有太多理由这么做
The cost of doing that is really high, so you have to figure out
这样做的成本真的很高 所以你必须弄清楚
do you want to spend a bunch of dev effort
你想花一大笔开发工作吗
in making this gimmick that's going to get really old and lots of people
在制作这个噱头的过程中 会有很多人
are going to get annoyed or frustrated?
会不会感到恼火或沮丧？
So you just don't do that.
所以你不能这么做
In the back there.
就在后面
AUDIENCE: You mentioned that you could cache some stuff--
观众：你提到你可以缓存一些东西--
things in the pipeline for some of the lighting plots--
一些照明场景正在酝酿之中--
earlier.
早些时候
I'm wondering if there were any other kind of hardware hacks
我想知道有没有其他类型的硬件黑客
that you do in order to keep the targets that you want for the portal behavior?
这样做是为了保持门户行为所需的目标？
DAVE KIRCHER: So the question references how there were some pipeline
戴夫·科尔彻：所以这个问题提到了一些管道是如何存在的
restraints on the pixel queries.
对像素查询的限制
And if there were any hacks that we had to do to meet performance,
如果要达到性能要求 我们必须进行任何黑客攻击
I believe yes.
我相信是的
TEJEEV KOHLI: And any other stuff we did.
TEJEEV KOHLI：还有我们做过的任何其他事情
DAVE KIRCHER: Once again, I'm going to have
戴夫·科尔彻：再一次 我将
to say that I did most of this stuff 10 years ago.
说我在10年前做了大部分这样的事情
I can't think of anything off the top of my head.
我脑子里想不出任何东西来
There wasn't a whole lot.
并不是很多
TEJEEV KOHLI: We did stuff with the paint.
TEJEEV KOHLI：我们做了油漆方面的工作
I don't know if we did a bunch of hacks, but one
我不知道我们是不是做了一堆黑客 但有一次
of the big hacks on the paint that we did was the paint that you're seeing
我们在油漆上做的大破解之一就是你所看到的油漆
is not the paint that's doing the painting.
不是画这幅画的油漆
So I mean that's, like, nobody can tell.
所以我的意思是 就像 没人知道
That's pretty good.
那真是太好了
But especially on multiplayer, the paint that the client is seeing
但尤其是在多人游戏中 客户看到的油漆
is not the paint that the server is seeing.
不是服务器看到的油漆
Because we couldn't transmit all that data,
因为我们无法传输所有的数据
so they're both generating their own data.
因此 它们都在生成自己的数据
But then the server is the only one doing the actual painting,
但是 服务器是唯一真正进行绘画的人
so all the blobs that the client is hitting in the world do nothing
因此 客户端在世界上遇到的所有斑点都不会执行任何操作
and the server blobs do the painting and then tell the client paint over there,
服务器斑点进行绘制 然后告诉客户端在那里进行绘制
paint over there.
在那边画画
So that's the kind of thing-- because the network bandwidth is pretty limited
所以这是一种事情--因为网络带宽相当有限
and there's a lot of paint flying through the world.
世界上有很多颜料在飞舞
So we couldn't just transmit all the paint all the time,
所以我们不能一直把所有的油漆都传输出去
so they all generate their own paint.
所以它们都会生成自己的油漆
Blobs that are through the world, and then the painting
遍及世界的斑点 然后是画
itself happened on the server and then that gets transmitted.
它本身发生在服务器上 然后它被传输
But the paint flying through the air is different on everyone,
但在空气中飞舞的油漆对每个人来说都是不同的
but it's random enough that you can't really tell.
但它的随机性很强 你真的看不出来
AUDIENCE: Is Half-Life 3 going to have portals?
观众：《半条命3》会有门户吗？
TEJEEV KOHLI: I don't know.
TEJEEV Kohli：我不知道
DAVE KIRCHER: No comment.
戴夫·柯尔彻：无可奉告
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Probably not.
大概不会吧
In all seriousness, after the initial Portal came out,
严肃地说 在最初的门户网站问世后
one of the other experiments was not only what does multiplayer look like,
另一个实验不仅是多人游戏的样子
but how fun is this in a Half-Life environment?
但在半条命的环境中 这有多有趣呢？
And it turns out that the way that Half-Life is made,
事实证明 半条命的制作方式
there are a whole lot of slightly scripted sequences to make things work.
有一大堆略微照本宣科的序列可以让事情运转起来
And so the way those levels are designed are
因此 这些级别的设计方式是
fundamentally different than Portal levels
与门户级别完全不同
and they basically just break down.
它们基本上就会分解
So if there were portals in Half-Life, then Half-Life
因此 如果《半条命》中有传送门 那么《半条命》
would seem a lot more like Portal.
看起来更像门户网站
TEJEEV KOHLI: If you think about a Portal level, it's pretty constrained.
TEJEEV Kohli：如果你考虑门户级别 它是相当受限制的
The sight lines are pretty constrained.
视线是相当有限的
The level takes place in a box.
这一关发生在一个盒子里
You can't see really far.
你看不到很远
There's a lot of kinks in the walls so you can't see all the way to the end.
墙壁上有很多弯折 所以你看不到尽头
Half-Life levels aren't designed like that at all.
半衰期水平完全不是这样设计的
So you would just go in a level and make portals all the way to the exit
所以你只需要进入一个关口 做一个通向出口的入口
and then skip all the game play.
然后跳过所有的游戏
I mean there are probably mods that allow you to do that,
我的意思是 可能有MODS允许你这样做
but I think the games themselves and the mechanics are fundamentally
但我认为游戏本身和机制从根本上来说
different enough that I don't think they interact really well.
差异足够大 我认为他们的互动不是很好
Unless both of them change or one of them
除非他们两个都改变或者其中一个改变
changes a lot so it's no longer the game you wanted.
变化很大 所以它不再是你想要的游戏
I think you were up first.
我想你是第一个上台的
Yeah.
嗯
AUDIENCE: You mentioned that you had done, like, a student game project
观众：你提到过你做了一个学生游戏项目
before you got hired by Valve?
在你被Valve雇用之前？
What was the story there?
那里的故事是什么？
TEJEEV KOHLI: So the question was asking about our student game projects.
TEJEEV Kohli：所以问题是关于我们的学生游戏项目
So Dave worked-- we both went to a school in Redmond called DigiPen.
所以戴夫工作了--我们都去了雷德蒙德的一所名叫DigiPen的学校
Dave went there before I did.
戴夫在我之前去过那里
DAVE KIRCHER: I graduated in 2005.
戴夫·科尔彻：我是2005年毕业的
I worked on a game called Narbacular Drop.
我参与了一个叫纳巴卡拉投掷的游戏
Which if you Google for it, it will be the only result
如果你在谷歌上搜索 这将是唯一的结果
because the name was chosen so that would be the only result on Google.
因为这个名字的选择是为了让它成为谷歌上唯一的搜索结果
If you could spell it, good luck.
如果你会拼写 祝你好运
And so that was our senior project at DigiPen--
这就是我们在DigiPen的高级项目--
my team at the time.
我当时的团队
And so we ended up through a very convoluted long story showing
所以我们结束了一个非常错综复杂的长篇大论
that at Valve, and they hired us on the spot
在Valve 他们当场雇用了我们
to basically recreate those mechanics for them.
基本上为他们重新创造了这些机制
And that was actually-- there wasn't a whole lot
这实际上是--没有太多
of confidence at the time that would actually ship, but it became Portal.
当时的信心 这将实际发货 但它成为门户网站
So it seemed like a good thing.
因此 这似乎是一件好事
TEJEEV KOHLI: Yeah, and I was part of a team that made "Tag--
TEJEEV Kohli：是的 我是制作“标签”的团队的一员
The Power of Paint," the video I showed with a paint gun, and that
我用喷漆枪展示的视频《油漆的力量》
was our team's junior project at DigiPen.
是我们团队在DigiPen的初级项目
And same thing, Valve saw it a couple of times
同样的事情 Valve看了几次
and hired the entire team to come work on that mechanic at Valve.
并雇佣了整个团队来为Valve的那个机械师工作
And then once we got there, it became obvious to try to integrate it
一旦我们到达那里 就很明显地要尝试将它整合在一起
into Portal 2 and that's how we start working on Portal 2
进入传送门2 这就是我们如何开始在传送门2上工作
and that's how the Portal 2 gels came about.
这就是传送门2凝胶的起源
AUDIENCE: The paints and gels which were introduced as a mechanic in Portal 2
观众：《传送门2》中作为机械师介绍的油漆和凝胶
ended up being part of the story as well.
最终也成为了故事的一部分
Can you talk about how some mechanics end up affecting the story
你能谈谈一些机械师是如何影响故事的吗？
and how story elements end up affecting the mechanics?
以及故事元素最终是如何影响机械的？
TEJEEV KOHLI: The question was about how the story and the game mechanics
TEJEEV Kohli：问题是故事和游戏机制是如何
interact and how one affects the other.
互动以及一个人如何影响另一个人
So the way at least in Portal 2, and I think Portal 1 was very similar.
所以至少在传送门2 我认为传送门1非常相似
The way it kind of works with Valve is we don't really
它与Valve的工作方式是 我们不是真的
have an overarching design for a design doc for the game before we start.
在我们开始之前 为游戏设计文档做一个总体设计
It's a lot of smaller things that we try to combine using similar techniques
我们尝试用类似的技术把很多小东西组合在一起
like what we discussed today.
就像我们今天讨论的那样
And the story kind of builds us out of using the same techniques.
而这个故事有点像是在使用相同的技术来构建我们
Because the way we kind of vet out most of our design decisions
因为我们审查大多数设计决策的方式
is by play testing.
是通过游戏测试
And the story follows a very similar plot but you don't really want one--
故事遵循了一个非常相似的情节 但你并不真的想要一个--
either one to override the other.
任何一个都不能覆盖另一个
Because if you see the game, like if I make a bunch--
因为如果你看了比赛 比如我做了一大堆--
if we have a team that made a bunch of puzzles
如果我们有一个团队制作了一堆拼图
for the game that haven't been very play tested.
对于这款游戏来说 这款游戏还没有经过充分的测试
And then the writer comes in and does a bunch of writing for it
然后编剧走进来 为它写了一大堆东西
and then you realize three weeks later that half these levels aren't shipping
然后三周后 你意识到有一半的水平没有发货
anymore because they didn't test well, then
再也没有了 因为他们考试不好 然后
you made a bunch of dependencies that didn't really work.
您创建了一大堆不起作用的依赖项
Portal was lucky in that the puzzles themselves are compartmentalized
门户是幸运的 因为拼图本身是被隔开的
as you enter the elevator.
当你进入电梯时
Or you exit the elevator, you do a puzzle, and enter the elevators.
或者你走出电梯 做一个拼图 然后进入电梯
So they're all pretty compartmentalized.
所以他们都是被划分得很小的
And a lot of the writing that was done for it was essentially just jokes.
而且很多为它写的文章基本上都是笑话
So a lot of those jokes do fit in to most of the puzzles.
因此 这些笑话中的许多确实适用于大多数谜题
So the puzzle can change and the joke can just be inserted into it.
因此 谜题可以改变 笑话可以插入其中
But for the overarching story of the game,
但对于这场比赛的核心故事来说
I think that required a lot more collaboration.
我认为这需要更多的合作
So the writers were on-site.
所以编剧们都在现场
They were Valve employees and they were sitting in the same room
他们是Valve的员工 他们坐在同一个房间里
as us watching us play test, bouncing back and forth ideas.
当我们看着我们玩测试 来回跳跃的想法
And we used-- we had GLaDOS for most of the game.
我们使用--我们在游戏的大部分时间里都使用GLaDOS
And the voice artist was local, so we had her come in many times
而配音艺人是当地人 所以我们让她来了很多次
and record a bunch of lines.
录下一大串台词
We also used some like fake online robot voice for a while,
我们还在网上使用了一些类似于假机器人的声音
but those are hard to judge because the play testers almost
但这些都很难判断 因为游戏测试者几乎
never laugh at those jokes.
不要因为这些笑话而发笑
Because the robot always doesn't really know how to speak them.
因为机器人总是不知道如何说这些话
But it sounds like a robot so it's not it's better than nothing.
但它听起来像个机器人 所以它不是 总比什么都没有强
It's better than just putting text on the screen, which we also
这比仅仅在屏幕上显示文本要好得多 我们还
did for a while.
有一段时间是这样
So with the writing, there's two things that you're trying to test, right?
所以在写作中 有两件事是你想测试的 对吗？
You're trying to test out the individual's jokes, and a lot of them
你在试着测试这个人的笑话 而且有很多
can be transported to any level.
可以运输到任何级别
So they're not super dependent on the levels.
因此 他们不会过度依赖于这些水平
But then once the story starts coming together
但一旦故事开始发展起来
and starts taking shape, at that point you're making changes to the levels
并开始成形 在这一点上 你正在改变水平
to accommodate the story.
以适应这个故事
And from that point on, you have to have a pretty good amount of confidence
从那时起 你必须有相当大的信心
that these particular levels are going to ship in the game.
这些特定的关卡将在游戏中发布
And so that that starts happening I think fairly late
因此 我认为这种情况开始发生的时间相当晚
into our dev cycle at least.
至少进入我们的开发周期
There's always an overarching goal.
总有一个压倒一切的目标
There's always a goal of you're trying to capture Wheatley
总有一个目标是你想要抓到韦奕礼
or you're trying to go kill GLaDOS, but the exact mechanics of how that happens
或者你正试图杀死GlaDos 但这是如何发生的
doesn't come together until fairly late.
直到相当晚的时候才走到一起
Because you don't want to spend a bunch of time integrating
因为你不想花很多时间去整合
your story and your levels without having a bunch of confidence
你的故事和你的水平没有一堆自信
that these levels are actually good enough to ship.
这些级别实际上是足够好的 可以运输
Which we do have for a bunch of the game,
这是我们在游戏中的一大部分
but as new levels and new mechanics are being introduced,
但随着新水平和新机制的引入
it all kind of goes haywire.
这一切都有点失控了
So it's just mostly a pretty strong collaborative process
因此 这主要是一个相当强大的协作过程
between the writers and the designers and it all
在作家和设计师之间 以及这一切之间
goes back to the play testing.
回到话剧测试
AUDIENCE: Can you talk a little bit about how
听众：你能谈谈你是如何
the sound interacts with portals, like in 3-D positioning
声音与门户互动 就像在3D定位中一样
of the audio sources?
音频源的？
DAVE KIRCHER: So the question was how sound interacts with Portal.
戴夫·科尔彻：所以问题是声音如何与门户网站互动
And my memory's a little fuzzy.
我的记忆有点模糊
I'm pretty sure we tried to replicate a little bit using
我非常肯定我们尝试过复制一点 使用
just a simple-- basically the exact same solution as with our lighting.
这只是一个简单的解决方案--基本上与我们的照明方案完全相同
Where it's like we have a sample point in front of a portal and we
这就像我们在门户前有一个样本点 我们
have an emitter on the other side.
在另一边安装一个发射器
I can't remember if we shipped that way.
我不记得我们是不是那样装船的
TEJEEV KOHLI: I think we did.
TEJEEV KOHLI：我想我们做到了
DAVE KIRCHER: Yeah.
戴夫·科尔彻：是的
TEJEEV KOHLI: I think there's a microphone or in-game microphone
TEJEEV Kohli：我认为有一个麦克风或游戏中的麦克风
and an in-game speaker on the portals on both sides.
在两边的门户上都有一个游戏中的扬声器
So if you're on this side of the portal, you'll
所以如果你在传送门的这一边 你会
hear what's happening on the other side.
听听另一边发生了什么
Pretty sure that's how we shipped.
我很确定我们就是这么装船的
DAVE KIRCHER: Yeah, but I don't think we made any special concessions
戴夫·科尔彻：是的 但我不认为我们有什么特别的让步
to make it seem like it was going through a tunnel or anything like that.
让它看起来像是在穿过隧道或类似的东西
We just wanted to make sure you could hear what was going on.
我们只是想确保你能听到发生了什么
TEJEEV KOHLI: Not through the portals specifically.
TEJEEV Kohli：不是专门通过门户网站
I know there was a bunch of stuff we did for the tractor beam.
我知道我们为拖拉机光束做了一堆东西
Like when you head to the tractor beam, it
就像当你走向拖拉机光束时 它
kind of fuzzles everything else around you and muddles the sound a little bit.
这会让你周围的一切变得模糊 也会让声音变得有点混乱
But going through the portals themselves,
但是通过入口本身
I don't think there's anything specific we did there.
我不认为我们在那里做了什么特别的事情
At least not that I can-- it's been a long time.
至少我不能--已经很长时间了
DAVE KIRCHER: It's been a long time.
戴夫·科尔彻：好久不见了
AUDIENCE: What were examples of puzzle games
观众：有哪些益智游戏的例子？
that inspired you when you making your games?
当你制作游戏的时候 你受到了什么启发？
TEJEEV KOHLI: Uh, Portal.
TEJEEV Kohli：嗯 门户网站
[LAUGHING]
[笑]
The question was, what puzzle games inspired us
问题是 是什么益智游戏启发了我们
when we were making our game?
当我们在做游戏的时候？
DAVE KIRCHER: I can't think of a strong inspiration.
戴夫·科尔彻：我想不出有什么强烈的灵感
I'm mostly a code guy, so I didn't do a whole lot of the actual puzzle design.
我主要是一个程序员 所以我没有做很多实际的拼图设计
But when I'm thinking back, we didn't have a whole lot of sources
但当我回想起来 我们没有太多的消息来源
to draw on because it was a fairly new concept in general.
可以借鉴 因为总的来说 这是一个相当新的概念
I can't think of any sources I drew on.
我想不出任何我所依赖的消息来源
I mean--
我是说
TEJEEV KOHLI: I wasn't kidding when I said Portal.
TEJEEV Kohli：我说的门户网站不是开玩笑的
When we were making Tag, I think Portal had come out a year
当我们制作TAG的时候 我想门户网站已经推出了一年
or two earlier before that and was really good and a big success.
在那之前的一两年里 它真的很好 取得了巨大的成功
And we were trying to learn from how they were
我们试着学习他们是如何
teaching the players different things.
教球员们不同的东西
And that's one of the biggest things we took away
这是我们从一个
in our student game was how do you teach players different mechanics?
在我们的学生游戏中 你如何教玩家不同的机制？
And I think Portal did a really good job of that.
我认为门户网站做得很好
By teaching by doing instead of by showing.
通过做而不是展示来教学
So like the players doing all the stuff and then
就像球员们做所有的事情
figuring it out instead of someone showing a video
而不是让别人看一段视频
or just telling the player, hey, here's what do you do next, and then go
或者只是告诉玩家 嘿 这是你接下来要做的 然后去
and doing that.
做这些事
So we tried to take that at heart, and as we
所以我们试着把它放在心上 当我们
were doing in our game introducing new paints and new mechanics,
在我们的游戏中引入了新的颜料和新的机制
doing it the same way where we introduce them in a way
我们用同样的方式来介绍它们
that the usage is obvious enough that the player will try it out.
使用方法足够明显 玩家会尝试它
And when they try it out and it works, they feel really good about it.
当他们尝试它 它的工作 他们感觉真的很好
Because they feel like they figured it out instead of us doing all the work
因为他们觉得是他们自己想出来的而不是我们来做所有的工作
and showing them what to do.
告诉他们该怎么做
So a lot of that kind of was a specific thing that we took from Portal
所以很多这类的东西都是我们从门户网站上拿来的
and trying to do it in our game.
并尝试在我们的游戏中做到这一点
AUDIENCE: How many people did it take to create these two games, Portal
观众：《传送门》 这两款游戏需要多少人来创作
and Portal 2, across the different functional units--
和传送门2 在不同的功能单元--
development, writers, and the rest?
发展 作家 和其他人
TEJEEV KOHLI: So the question was about how many people
TEJEEV KOHLI：所以问题是有多少人
it took to make Portal and Portal 2.
制作《传送门》和《传送门2》的关键
Portal 1 was a pretty small team for the most part.
传送门1在很大程度上是一个相当小的团队
DAVE KIRCHER: So Portal 2 started as the seven people that worked on--
戴夫·基尔彻：所以《传送门2》一开始是由七个人负责的--
TEJEEV KOHLI: Portal 1.
一号传送门
DAVE KIRCHER: Yeah.
戴夫·奇彻：是的
Sorry, Portal 1 started with the seven people
抱歉传送门1一开始
that worked on Narbacular Drop directly transplanted.
直接移植到Narbacular Drop上
And then we started working fairly early with two writers.
然后我们很早就开始和两个作家合作
And we were leveraging other people at Valve
我们利用Valve的其他人
to answer questions and help us hit the ground running as far
回答问题 帮助我们尽快
as how to use the engine.
如何使用引擎
But it was mostly just those nine people working day to day.
但主要是那九个人每天工作
And then Portal 2 ballooned quite a bit.
然后传送门2膨胀了很多
TEJEEV KOHLI: Portal 2 was a much bigger team.
TEJEEV Kohli：传送门2是一支更大的球队
By the time I joined Valve in 2009, I think there was already
到我2009年加入Valve时 我认为已经有了
a pretty big Portal 2 team.
一支相当庞大的门户2团队
They already had a field the mechanics figured out.
他们已经有了机械师计算出的领域
The game was pretty different from what you see now, but at that point
这场比赛和你现在看到的完全不同 但在那个时候
it was already maybe 10, 12 people.
可能已经有10到12个人了
And then like it slowly increased.
然后喜欢它慢慢增加
Like we were four or five that got hired for our paint game.
就像我们有四五个人被雇来玩我们的彩绘游戏
So we joined that team.
所以我们加入了那个团队
And then I think by the end of it, there were probably
然后我想 到最后 可能会有
close to 40, 50 people working on it.
有近四五十个人在做这件事
That was towards the very end because we had to ship on two consoles and PC
那是在接近尾声的时候 因为我们必须在两台游戏机和PC上发货
and we had a whole co-op mechanic.
我们有一个完整的合作社机械师
And there was a whole co-op campaign be worked on separately
有一个单独的合作组织活动
as well as a single player one.
以及一名单人球员
So it was a pretty big team by the end of it.
所以在比赛结束时 这是一支相当强大的球队
Much bigger than Portal 1.
比1号传送门大得多
And the game itself I think is much bigger than Portal 1 as well.
而且我认为游戏本身也比传送门1大得多
I think the single player campaign itself is probably
我认为单人竞选本身很可能是
more than twice as long.
两倍多的时间
And the campaign-- the co-op one is probably also that big.
而这场运动--合作组织的运动可能也有那么大
DAVE KIRCHER: I remember in Portal 1 we would have to do frequent integration
Dave Kircher：我记得在门户1中 我们必须进行频繁的整合
testing and I think I got my play time on Portal 1 down to like 45 minutes
测试 我想我在门户1上的播放时间缩短到了45分钟
and Portal 2 is several hours.
2号门有几个小时的路程
TEJEEV KOHLI: Yeah.
TEJEEV KOHLI：是的
So it's a much bigger game, so it took a lot more people.
所以这是一个更大的游戏 所以它需要更多的人
AUDIENCE: How does the game engine that you used compare to Unity?
观众：你使用的游戏引擎和Unity相比怎么样？
Is it more straight-up C programming from scratch,
它是更直接的从头开始的C编程
or is it a lot of the drag-and-drop stuff you see?
或者是你看到的很多拖放式的东西？
TEJEEV KOHLI: So the question is how did our game engine
TEJEEV Kohli：所以问题是我们的游戏引擎是如何
compare to something like Unity.
请比较一下像“团结”这样的东西
For both Portal and Portal 2, we used Source,
对于门户和门户2 我们都使用了源
which is our in-house game engine.
这是我们内部的游戏引擎
And it's very different from how Unity works.
这与Unity的工作原理有很大不同
So the way Unity works is mostly like a really big editor.
因此 Unity的工作方式很像一个真正的大编辑
Like what you're seeing in the editor is the game essentially.
就像你在编辑器中看到的一样 本质上就是游戏
Like all the entities and stuff are loaded.
就像所有的实体和东西都加载了一样
Obviously more stuff gets loaded at one time.
显然 一次装载更多的东西
But what you're seeing is what you're getting.
但你所看到的就是你所得到的
Whereas the way Source works is it's got a bunch of these discrete tools that
而源代码的工作方式是它有一堆这样的离散工具
make stuff.
制造一些东西
So there's a level editor, which is where you make your level.
所以有一个关卡编辑器 你可以在那里设置关卡
And then you import that into the game and you run the game separately.
然后你把它导入到游戏中 然后你单独运行游戏
And what you're seeing in a level editor is not what you see in the game
你在关卡编辑器中看到的并不是你在游戏中看到的
because a lot of the entities and stuff don't translate to the editor.
因为很多实体和东西不会翻译给编辑
A lot of the lighting and stuff has to be pre-baked.
很多照明和材料都必须预先烘焙
Unity has some pre-baked lighting as well.
Unity也有一些预烘焙的照明
But in the way it worked in Source--
但在源码中 它的工作方式--
Source I think is a combination of a bunch of discrete tools
我认为源代码是一系列离散工具的组合
for each different aspect of the game.
对于这场比赛的每一个不同方面
So I get a separate particles editor, separate model editor,
所以我有一个单独的粒子编辑器 单独的模型编辑器
separate editor for VO and the face poser, and the separate level editor.
VO和Face Poser的单独编辑器 以及单独的关卡编辑器
And then there's a game engine that takes the compiled versions of all--
然后有一个游戏引擎 它接受所有的编译版本--
compiled outputs of all those things and then puts them in the game engine
编译所有这些内容的输出 然后将它们放入游戏引擎
and combines them together.
并将它们结合在一起
And then all the code is pretty much exclusively C++.
然后所有的代码几乎都是C++
I don't think there's really anything else.
我不认为真的有什么其他的
There might be a couple a handful of things that are not,
可能有几件事不是
but all the tools are C++.
但是所有的工具都是C++
All the game engine all the runtime code is all C++.
所有的游戏引擎 所有的运行时代码都是C++
Source 2 is a little bit different, but still going forward on that front,
来源2有点不同 但在这方面仍在向前发展
I'm not trying to do what Unity's doing.
我不想做Unity正在做的事
Because Unity is more of your running scripts--
因为Unity更像是你的运行脚本--
C# scripts-- and then you're just compiling them while the editor's going
C#脚本--然后您只需在编辑器离开时编译它们
and the rapid iteration and stuff.
以及快速迭代之类的东西
Source doesn't really have that same model of working.
来源并不是真的有相同的工作模式
But the advantage is that we control all of it
但好处是我们控制了一切
and then the ceiling for what we can produce
然后是我们能生产的产品的上限
is theoretically quite a bit higher.
从理论上讲是相当高的
So there's tradeoffs to it.
因此 这是有权衡的
And also we make all our tools and all our engine stuff in-house
此外 我们所有的工具和引擎材料都是在内部生产的
and we're the primary customer for our games.
我们是我们游戏的主要客户
So we're not trying to do what you Unity is
所以我们并不想做你所做的
doing and trying to service to anyone out there who wants to make anything.
为任何想要制造任何东西的人服务并努力为他们服务
And Unity has thousands of people working on their engine
Unity有成千上万的人在修理他们的发动机
and we have quite a few orders of magnitude less.
而且我们有相当多的小数量级
But I think we are aware of all the tradeoffs we're making.
但我认为我们意识到了我们正在进行的所有权衡
We're not trying not to do what they're doing.
我们并没有试图不去做他们正在做的事情
We're just seeing-- and we're learning from them, too,
我们只是在看--我们也在向他们学习
and Source 2 has taken a few cues from stuff like Utility and stuff
《源码2》从诸如Utility和Things之类的东西中得到一些启示
like Unreal.
就像虚幻一样
Trying to be more user friendly even to our own customers, internal employees.
努力对我们自己的客户、内部员工变得更友好
But it's not like--
但这并不像...
the way of working is very different between Source and Unity.
在源头和统一之间 工作方式是非常不同的
I think we're good.
我觉得我们很好
All right, well, thanks again for having us.
好的 再次感谢你邀请我们
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
COLTON OGDEN: Thank you all so much for coming.
科尔顿·奥格登：非常感谢你们的到来
So there's some extra pizza outside, but that was Portal Problems.
所以外面有一些多余的披萨 但那是门户网站的问题
So thank you very much.
所以非常感谢你们